不，这是我最无能为力的题目之一。
No, it is one of the topics that I am most incapable of.
No, es uno de los temas que me incapaz más.
我分居并不是因为我像个女人，瓦伦蒂娜今天很好。
I live in separation not because I am like a woman and Valentina is fine today.
Yo vivo en la separación no porque yo soy como mujer y Valentina hoy está bien.
但显然我的孩子们也这样做，只是这让我受伤。
But obviously my children do too, except that it hurts me.
Pero obvio que mis hijos también, salvo que a mí duele.
碰巧我的父母在我很小的时候就分开了，这就像所有的事情都回到了我的身边。
It happened to me that my parents also separated when I was little and it's like all that comes back to me.
A mí me pasó de que mis papás se separaron también cuando yo era chica y es como que me vuelve todo eso.
我
i
好的，亲爱的，谢谢你来到这里。
Okay, dear, thank you for coming here.
Valen, querida, gracias por venir acá.
重塑阿根廷的生活。
Remaking life in Argentina.
Rehaciendo la vida en Argentina.
在足球世界和恩佐之手带领你之后......
After the world of football and the hand of Enzo has taken you...
Después que el mundo del fútbol y de la mano de Enzo te ha llevado...
探索不同的领域。
to explore different territories.
a explorar distintos territorios.
你好吗？
How are you?
¿Cómo estás?
你回国怎么样了？
How is your return home?
¿Cómo está tu vuelta a casa?
好，非常好。
Good, very good.
Bien, muy bien.
渐渐地，我们正在组织自己、适应自己，但一切都很好。
Little by little we are organizing ourselves, accommodating ourselves, but well.
De a poco nos vamos organizando, acomodando, pero bien.
你去那里多久了？
How long have you been there?
¿Hace cuánto está allá?
几个月？
Few months?
¿Poquitos meses?
现在已经两个月了。
And it will be two months now.
Y dos meses van a ser ahora.
几个月的？
Of the months?
¿Dos meses?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
没有什么！
Nothing!
¡Nada!
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
和恩佐一起生活了多少年？
A life with Enzo for how many years?
Una vida junto a Enzo de cuántos años?
六年了。
Six years.
Seis años.
六年了。
Six years.
Seis años.
这段爱情故事是如何开始的？
And how did that love story begin?
¿Y cómo empezó esa historia de amor?
我们相遇了，我们来自圣马丁的同一个街区。
We met, we are from the same neighborhood of San Martín.
Nosotros nos conocimos, somos del mismo barrio de San Martín.
所以我们有一群共同的朋友，最终我们互相认识了。
So we had a group of friends in common and we ended up getting to know each other.
Así que teníamos un grupo de amigos en común y nos terminamos de conocer.
我的家人刚刚去 Mar del Tuyú 过夏天，他们总是去那里，所以我们最终在那里见面。
My family had just gone to Mar del Tuyú for the summer and the family always goes there, so we ended up meeting there.
Justo mi familia había ido a veranear a Mar del Tuyú y la familia siempre va ahí, así que nos terminamos de conocer ahí.
在海里。
there in the sea.
ahí en el mar.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
他们开始以男朋友的​​身份出去？
And they started going out there as boyfriends?
¿Y empezaron a salir ahí como novios?
不，我们在那里，伙计，我们是在那年夏天认识的。
No, we were there, dude, we met that summer.
No, ahí estuvimos, tipo, nos conocimos ese verano.
然后我们渐行渐远，到了年底，或多或少，十一月份我们又见面了。
Then we grew apart and at the end of the year, more or less, in November we saw each other again.
después nos distanciamos y a fin de año, más o menos, en noviembre nos volvimos a ver.
他们是什么，16岁？
They were what, 16 years old?
¿Tenían cuánto, 16 años?
是的，16岁和17岁，那年夏天。
Yes, 16 and 17, there that summer.
Sí, 16 y 17, ahí en ese verano.
非常小。
Very small.
Muy chiquitos.
两个人单独在一起吗？
Were the two alone?
¿Los dos estaban solos?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你已经喜欢他的某些方面了吗？
And did you already like something about him?
¿Y algo te gustaba ya de él?
是的，确实有一些事情，但仍然是，我不知道，我不想参与其中，但是......
Yes, something was, but it was still like, I don't know, I didn't want to get involved, but...
Sí, algo sí, pero todavía era como, no sé, no me quería meter, pero...
事情一点一点地发生了。
Little by little it happened.
De a poco fue pasando.
足球世界显然已经进入了他的生活，
The world of football was obviously already in his life,
El mundo del fútbol ya estaba obviamente en su vida,
但他并不是今天所皈依的那个人。
but he was not who he converted to this day.
pero no era quien se convirtió al día de hoy.
伴随的过程是什么样的？
What was that accompanying process like?
¿Cómo fue ese proceso de acompañar?
他们从 Mar de Tushu 回来，他们仍然是朋友。
They return from Mar de Tushu, they are still friends.
Vuelven de Mar de Tushu, siguen siendo amigos.
当时他还没有进入River的预备队。
At that time he was not yet in River's reserve.
En ese momento no estaba todavía en la reserva de River.
我少了一个类别，然后就在那个夏天
I was in one category less and then there just that summer
estaba en una categoría menos y después ahí justo ese verano
当我开始和他约会时，他们把他列入保留名单，他再也没有出来。
When I started dating him, they put him on reserve and he didn't come out again.
Cuando yo ya empecé a salir con él, lo suben a reserva y ahí no salió más.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你喜欢足球世界吗？
Did you like the world of football?
¿Te gustaba el mundo del fútbol?
你觉得怎么样？
What did you think?
¿Qué te parecía?
是的，我有两个弟弟。
Yes, I have two younger brothers.
Sí, yo tengo dos hermanos más chicos.
他们总是踢足球之类的，所以或多或少……足球就在你的生活中。
And they always played soccer and stuff, so more or less... Soccer was in your life.
Y siempre jugaron al fútbol y eso, así que más o menos... El fútbol estaba en tu vida.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
但是，成为一名足球运动员的妻子，在他长大的过程中，你是否也想过并梦想过呢？
But about becoming the wife of a soccer player, were you thinking and dreaming about it as he grew up?
Pero esto de convertirte en la mujer de un jugador de fútbol, ¿lo ibas pensando y soñando a medida que él iba creciendo?
不，因为我想我从来没有想象过他会达到他现在的成就。
No, because I don't think I ever imagined that he would get to where he got.
No, porque creo que nunca me imaginé que él iba a llegar a donde llegó.
是的，显然我对他有信心等等，但是是的，我从没想过会发展到这一点。
Yes, obviously I had faith in him and so on but yes, I never thought it would come to that.
Sí, obvio que le tenía fe y demás pero sí, nunca pensé que iba a llegar a eso.
为国家队效力，赢得世界杯。
to play for the national team, to win the World Cup.
a jugar en la selección, a ganar la Copa del Mundo.
是的，去欧洲踢球，等等。
Yes, to play in Europe, all that.
Sí, a jugar en Europa, todo eso sí.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
疯狂的。
Crazy.
Una locura.
好吧，River 看到了，说我想要，然后开始比赛。
Well, River sees it, says I want it, starts playing.
Bueno y River lo ve, dice lo quiero, empieza a jugar.
那里的事情开始顺利进行，因为人们想象在足球世界中一切都已准备就绪，而你来了
Things start to work well there, because one imagines that in the world of football everything is served and you came
ahí empiezan a funcionar las cosas bien, porque uno se imagina que en el mundo del fútbol todo está servido y ustedes venían
真的，要努力去做。
really, to work hard at it.
de verdad, de laburarla mucho.
您当时已经在学习法律了吗？
Were you already studying law at that time?
¿Vos estudiabas abogacía en ese momento ya?
是的，我毕业后就开始学习。
Yes, I started studying when I finished school.
Sí, yo empecé a estudiar cuando terminé el colegio.
我在那里工作过，我在那里工作过。
and I worked there, I am there and I worked.
y ahí trabajaba, estoy ahí y trabajaba.
你在哪里工作？
Where did you work?
¿Dónde trabajabas?
首先我在一家肉馅卷饼店工作，然后在市中心的一个呼叫中心工作。
First I worked in an empanadas house and then in a call center, downtown.
Primero trabajé en una casa empanadas y después en un call center, en el centro.
所以没什么，当我开始做的时候，我在肉馅卷饼屋工作，而我在那里学习
So nothing, when I started with that I worked at the empanada house and while I was studying there
Así que nada, cuando empecé con eso trabajé en la casa de empanadas y mientras ahí estudiaba
在 UBA，然后是的，我转到了呼叫中心。
at the UBA and then yes, I changed to the call center.
en la UBA y después sí, me cambié para el call center.
我也在那里学习，并且成功地怀孕了九个月。
And there I also studied and I managed to perform up to nine months pregnant.
y ahí también estudiaba y llegué a rendir hasta nueve meses embarazada.
因为在那里他们开始和恩佐约会，我就在里弗的保留区。
Because there they started dating Enzo, I was in River's reserve.
Porque ahí empezaron a salir con Enzo, yo estaba en la reserva de River.
你怀了奥利维亚吗？
Are you pregnant with Olivia?
¿Vos quedás embarazada de Olivia?
当奥利维亚在保留地时，我怀上了他。
I got pregnant with Olivia when he was on the reservation.
Yo quedé embarazada de Olivia cuando él estaba en la reserva.
而且它也是在大流行中，因为婴儿是在大流行中出生的。
And it is in a pandemic too, because the baby was born in a pandemic.
Y está en pandemia también, porque la nena nació en pandemia.
所以当一切才刚刚开始的时候……你们住在一起吗？
So when everything was just starting... Are you living together?
Así que cuando todo recién arrancaba... ¿Está vivía juntos?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
啊，他们已经在那里了。
Ah, they were already there.
Ah, ya estaban.
你们在一起住了多久？
How long did you live together?
¿A cuánto tiempo se fueron a vivir juntos?
不，我想是三个月后。
No, after three months, I think.
No, a los tres meses, creo.
是的，一切都很快。
Yes, all fast.
Sí, todo rápido.
我的意思是，除了你的节目之外，我们还对彼此有一些了解。
I mean, in addition to your show, we still get to know each other a little.
O sea, además de tu show, nos seguimos conociendo un poco.
三个月后，是的，我们搬到了一起。
Three months later, yes, we moved in together.
A los tres meses, sí, nos fuimos a vivir juntos.
我们住在乌尔基扎别墅。
We lived in Villa Urquiza.
Vivíamos en Villa Urquiza.
那些男性兄弟，你们的老人，怎么说呢？
What did the male brothers, your old people, say?
¿Ahí qué decían los hermanos varones, tus viejos?
除了那些兄弟之外，他们都更大
well apart from those brothers they are all bigger
bien aparte de los hermanos de esos son todos más grandes
对他的家人来说也很好，对我的家人来说也很好。
also and the part for his family is good and for mine too.
también y la parte por la familia de él re bien y por la mía también.
他们没有告诉你，嘿，好吧，等一下，不。
They didn't tell you, hey, okay, wait a little, no.
No te decían, che, valen, espera un poco, no.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
不。
No.
不，没什么。
No, nothing.
No, nada.
好吧，三个月后他们住在一起，你就怀孕了玻利维亚。
Well, after three months they go to live together and you get pregnant Bolivia.
Bueno, a los tres meses se van a vivir juntos y quedás embarazada Bolivia.
是的，我不知道，六个月后我怀孕了。
Yes, at, I don't know, six months I got pregnant.
Sí, a los, no sé, seis meses quedo embarazada.
那一刻是什么样的？
And what was that moment like?
¿Y cómo fue ese momento?
不，很好。
No, fine.
No, bien.
一开始，很震惊。
At first, shocking.
Al principio, chocante.
就好像我就在那里，我不知道，带着怀疑。
It was like I was there, I didn't know, with doubts.
Era como que estaba ahí, no sabía, con dudas.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
那好吧。
Oh well.
Pero bueno.
他对生活感到满意吗？
And he was happy with life?
¿Y él estaba feliz de la vida?
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
不，一开始不是。
No, not at first.
No, al principio no.
这就像更多……想象一下，它很密集。
It was like more... Imagine, it was dense.
Estaba como más... Imagínate, era denso.
我怀孕的时候我18岁。
When I got pregnant I was 18 years old.
Cuando yo quedé embarazada tenía 18 años.
很小，我们都是男孩
very small, we were both boys
muy chico, los dos eramos chicos
然后，是的，当他出生时，我 20 岁，然后 19 岁。
And then, yes, when he was born, I was 20 and then 19.
Y después, sí, cuando nació, yo tenía 20 y enzo 19.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
你是怎么发现自己怀上了奥利维亚的？
How did you find out you're pregnant with Olivia?
¿Cómo te enterás que estás embarazada de Olivia?
我发现是因为我开始感觉不好而且我已经说过了......
I found out because I started to feel bad and I already said...
Me enteré porque me empecé a sentir mal y yo ya dije...
奇怪的事情所以奇怪
strange something strange so
raro algo raro así que
我记得我在工作时在浴室里进行了 EVA 测试。
I remember that I took an EVA test at work, in the bathroom at work.
Me acuerdo que me hice un eva test en el trabajo, en el baño del trabajo.
在呼叫中心。
In the call center.
En el call center.
是的，在呼叫中心。
Yes, in the call center.
Sí, en el call center.
我很乐观。
And I'm positive.
Y yo positivo.
那就是你叫他的地方？
And that's where you called him?
¿Y ahí lo llamaste?
不，我到达时就告诉他了。
No, I told him when I arrived.
No, se lo dije cuando llegué.
我到了，我告诉他，一开始什么也没有。
I arrived, I told him and at first nothing.
Llegué, se lo dije y al principio nada.
不，也许他总是让我做我该做的事......
No, maybe he always told me to do what I...
No, igual él siempre en eso me dijo que haga lo que yo...
你感觉如何。
What you feel.
Lo que vos sientes.
是的，他在这方面一直很尊重我。
Yes, he always respected me in that.
Sí, en eso siempre me respetó.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
并不是他告诉我不，是或是，不，他告诉我按照我的感觉去做。
It's not that he told me no, yes or yes, no, he told me to do what I feel.
No es que me dijo no, sí o sí, no, me dijo que haga lo que yo sienta.
然后它开始...
And then it started to...
Y después se empezó a...
与肚子比较，与陪伴。
to compare with the belly and with accompanying you.
a compar con la panza y con acompañarte a vos.
是的，或多或少。
Yes, more or less.
Sí, más o menos.
显然，足球可以激发你的很多潜能。
Obviously, football brings out many things in you.
Obvio que el fútbol eso muchas cosas te saca.
去做超声波检查，因为也许他正在训练或者有一场比赛，所以......
to go to ultrasounds, because maybe he was training or he had a match, so...
de ir a ecografías, porque capaz justo él entrenaba o justo él tenía un partido, así que...
没什么，我一个人做的比什么都重要。
Nothing, I did it alone more than anything.
Nada, yo lo hacía sola más que nada.
是的，有些事情显然......
Yes, and some things obviously...
Sí, y algunas cosas obviamente...
有些事他在分娩，庆幸的是有些事他不在，他可以两者兼而有之
In some things he is in childbirth, it was fortunate that there are some who are not there, he can be in both
en algunas cosas está en el parto estuvo por suerte que hay algunos que no están él puede estar en los dos
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
奥利维亚出生在这里吗？
Was Olivia born here?
¿Olivia nació acá?
奥利出生在这里，是的，在阿根廷。
Oli was born here, yes, in Argentina.
Oli nació acá, sí, en Argentina.
当然，他已经……他还在河里。
And he was already... he was still in River, of course.
Y él ya estaba... él seguía en River, claro.
不，当...
No, when...
No, cuando...
不，当她出生时，她还在河流保护区，几个月后，她去了捍卫正义组织。
No, when she was born she was still in the River reserve and after a few months she went to Defensa y Justicia.
No, cuando nació ella sigue en la reserva de River y después a los meses va a Defensa y Justicia.
完美，但你仍然住在阿根廷。
Perfect, but you are still living here in Argentina.
Perfecto, pero todavía seguís viviendo acá en Argentina.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
疫情结束了吗？
Is the pandemic over?
¿Pasa la pandemia?
您是如何度过疫情的？
How did you get through the pandemic?
¿Cómo pasaste la pandemia?
那是为了……什么？
What was it like for...?
¿Cómo fue para...?
不，好吧，我们很好地度过了这一切。
No, well, we went through it well.
No, bien, la transitamos bien.
是的，幸运的是，是的。
Yes, luckily, yes.
Sí, por suerte, sí.
因为作为一个不停歇的人，有如此多的节奏、训练和一切，现在已经很困难了。
because being a man who doesn't stop, with so much pace and training and everything, now it has been difficult.
porque siendo un hombre que no para, con tanto ritmo y entrenamiento y todo, ahora ha sido difícil.
是的，不，玩。
Yes, no, play.
Sí, no, play.
然后。
then.
en ese momento.
有戏了。
There was the play.
Estaba la play.
这玩了一整天。
It was all day play.
Era todo el día play.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
奥利维亚有多少钱？
And how much did Olivia have?
¿Y Olivia cuánto tenía?
几个月，因为她出生在五月，所以那是整个大流行开始的时候。
months, because she was born in May, so that was when the whole pandemic began.
meses, porque ella nació en mayo, así que en plena fue cuando empezó toda la pandemia.
当奥利维亚将她抱在怀里，陪着你出生时……
And when Olivia held her in her arms and accompanied you to the birth...
Y cuando la tuvo Olivia en brazos y acompañarte al parto...
是的，你不能在那里起飞。
Yes, you can't take off there.
Sí, ahí no se puede despegar.
已经在那里了。
There it is already.
Ahí ya está.
不，是的。
No, yes.
No, sí.
原来是那个女孩来了。
It was the girl who had arrived.
Era la nena que había llegado.
是的，但直到今天。
Yes, but until today.
Sí, pero hasta el día de hoy.
哦，是吗？
Oh yeah?
¿Ah, sí?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
当然，对于女性来说，这种情况也会发生在父亲身上。
Of course, with women it happens with dads.
Claro, con las mujeres pasa con los papás.
我也是，是的，就是因为这个原因。
Me too, yes, for that reason.
A mí también, sí, por eso.
你看，妻子和父亲总是非常亲密。
You saw that the wife and the father are always super close.
Viste que la mujer y el padre siempre son súper unidos.
奥利维亚，当你第一次决定去外面生活时你多大了？
Olivia, how old were you when you first decided to go live outside?
Olivia, ¿cuántos meses tenía cuando le sale por primera vez ir a vivir afuera?
而他刚刚满两岁。
And he had just turned two years old.
Y había cumplido recién los dos años.
奥利维亚两岁了，她拿到了通行证。
Olivia was two years old and she got the pass.
Dos años Olivia tenía y le sale el pase.
我们就去葡萄牙。
And there we go to Portugal.
Y ahí vamos a Portugal.
一个葡萄牙。
a Portugal.
那是什么决定说，好吧，我们收拾行李，我陪你，我们一起走，我们是一家人？
What was that decision to say, well, we pack our bags, I'll accompany you, we go together, we are a family?
¿Cómo fue esa decisión de decir, bueno, hacemos las valijas, yo te acompaño, vamos juntos, somos una familia?
发生在我身上的事情是我已经和他住在一起了。
What happens is that what happened to me is that I already lived with him.
Lo que pasa es que a mí lo que me pasó es que yo ya vivía con él.
所以我已经和家人疏远了。
So I was already detached from my family.
Entonces yo como que ya estaba desprendida de mi familia.
我们住在附近的弗洛伦西亚巴雷拉，然后住在埃塞萨。
We kind of lived nearby in Florencia Varela, then we lived in Ezeiza.
tipo vivimos cerca ahí en Florencia Varela, después vivimos en Ezeiza.
就好像我的家人已经在很远的地方了，离开并没有花费我太多的钱。
It's like I already had my family far away and it didn't cost me that much to leave.
Es como que ya tenía a mi familia a lejos y no me costó tanto irme.
当他告诉你时，你还记得那天他告诉你，嘿，我们要住在国外吗？
When he told you, do you remember that day he told you, hey, we're going to live abroad?
Cuando él te dijo, ¿te acordás ese día que te dijo, che, nos vamos a vivir al exterior?
作为夫妻，住在外面是你们的梦想吗？
Was it a dream of yours as a couple to live outside?
¿Era un sueño de ustedes como pareja vivir afuera?
是的，我想是的，我看到他在陪着他，那是他的一个梦。
Yes, I think it was, I saw that he was accompanying him, it was a dream of his.
Sí, yo creo que era, yo vio que lo acompañaba él, era un sueño de él.
因为你还必须学会远离家人。
Because you also have to learn to be away from your family.
Porque también tenés que aprender a estar lejos de tu familia.
或与他交朋友。
or make friends with him.
o hacerte amiga de él.
日复一日的孤独，是的。
Being alone day to day, yes.
Estar solo el día a día, sí.
但是，嘿，它的好处还在于，嗯......
But hey, what's also good about it is that, well...
Pero bueno, también lo que tiene de bueno es que, pues...
只要你愿意，就可以随时邀请他们。
Invite them whenever you want.
invitarlos cuando quieras.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
还。
Also.
También.
并在那里。
And be there.
Y estar ahí.
那种可能性
That possibility
Esa posibilidad
他们有并且可以给票。
that they have and that they can give a ticket.
que tienen ellos y que puedan dar un pasaje.
但突然之间，在呼叫中心或肉馅卷饼屋工作，一切都让你付出代价。
But suddenly, everything costs you and working in a call center or an empanada house.
Pero de repente, de que todo te cueste y de trabajar de un call center o una casa de empanadas.
作为一名工人，生活改变了你，好吗？
and being a worker, life changes you, okay?
y ser una laburante, la vida te cambia, ¿vale?
是的，360。
Yes, 360.
Sí, 360.
这种变化是什么样的，你是如何应对它的，以及你是如何伴随它的。
What was that change like, how did you work on it and also how did you accompany it.
cómo fue ese cambio, cómo lo trabajaste vos y también cómo lo acompañaste.
恩佐因为他实力很强，还没有进入国家队。
to Enzo because he was very strong and had not yet made it to the national team.
a Enzo porque era muy fuerte y todavía no había llegado a la selección.
不。
No.
嗯，不，是的，它很强大。
Well, no, yes it was strong.
Bueno, no, sí fue fuerte.
但好吧，公司...
But well, the company of...
Pero bueno, la compañía de...
我估计我总是在最好的时候陪伴着他，总是……我很积极，我总是心情很好，一切，所以……
I estimate that I always accompanied him at the best time and always... I am very positive, I am always in a good mood, everything, so...
calculo que lo acompañé en siempre el mejor momento y siempre... yo soy muy positiva, siempre me la ando en buen humor, todo, así que...
就像，在那部分我认为我陪他很好。
Like, in that part I think I accompanied him quite well.
como que en esa parte creo que lo acompañé bastante bien.
当你到达葡萄牙时，困难吗？
When you arrived in Portugal, was it difficult?
Cuando llegaron a Portugal, ¿era difícil?
这会有多奇怪？
How weird is this going to be?
¿Qué raro va a ser esto?
不，我并没有花那么多钱。
No, it didn't cost me that much.
No, no me costó tanto.
不，很好。
No, fine.
No, bien.
幸运的是，很好。
Luckily, good.
Por suerte, bien.
这并没有让我付出代价。
It didn't cost me.
No me costó.
你们成为朋友了吗？
Did you become friends?
¿Te hiciste amigas?
是的，我可以自己做一些。
Yes, I was able to make some of my own.
Sí, me pude hacer algunas a mías.
无论如何，我在英格兰做了更多的事情。
I did more in England anyway.
Me hice más en Inglaterra igual.
葡萄牙 他们有多长？
Portugal how long were they?
¿Portugal cuánto tiempo estuvieron?
八个月。
Eight months.
Ocho meses.
八个月了，结果就出来了……
Eight months and there it comes out...
Ocho meses y ahí le sale...
他要去哪里？
Where is he going?
¿A dónde se va?
世界杯就要开始了。
There goes the world cup.
Ahí va el mundial.
啊，在葡萄牙中部它出现了......
Ah, in the middle of Portugal it comes out...
Ah, en el medio de Portugal sale...
世界杯。
The world cup.
El mundial.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
告诉我那个电话的事以及那个……太糟糕了。
Tell me about that call and that... Terrible.
Contame ese llamado y ese... Terrible.
因为有很大的变化。
Because there is the big change.
Porque ahí está el gran cambio.
是的，我们在葡萄牙，我记得我们很孤独，总是有人，但这次没有人。
Yes, we were in Portugal, I remember we were alone, there are always people and this time there was no one.
Sí, estábamos en Portugal, me acuerdo que estábamos solos, siempre hay gente y esta vez justo no había nadie.
我看到 Kenzo 做好了准备，他担心自己可能不在那里，而我看到了那些想要在那里的期望。
And I saw Kenzo getting ready, he was afraid that he might not be there and I saw those expectations of wanting to be there.
Y yo lo vi a Kenzo se repreparaba, él tenía miedo de capaz de que no esté y yo vio esas expectativas de querer estar.
我记得名单公布前的几个月......
and I remember that those months before the list came out...
y me acuerdo que esos meses previos a que salga la lista...
他吃得很好，不是吗？
He ate very well, didn't he?
Comía súper bien, ¿no?
你告诉他，在这里，你是软糖，他不会吃的。
You told him, here, you're a gummy, he wouldn't eat it.
Le decías, toma, que eres una gomita, no la comía.
无论你想象什么。
Whatever you imagine.
Lo que te imagines.
换句话说，他已经做好了心理准备。
In other words, he prepared himself mentally.
O sea, se preparaba mentalmente.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
精神上和身体上也是如此。
Mentally and physically too.
Mentalmente y físicamente también.
他训练超级，他双班训练，他重新准备。
He trained super, he trained double shifts, he reprepared.
Súper entrenaba, entrenaba doble turno, se repreparó.
所以，没什么，然后有一天……他们不是聊了很多吗？
So, nothing, and then one day... Didn't they talk much?
Así que, nada, y después un día... ¿No hablaban mucho?
我希望他给你打电话。
I hope he calls you.
Ojalá que te llame.
他们谈过吗？
Did they talk about it?
¿Lo hablaban?
你们之间有问题吗？
Was it an issue between you?
¿Era un tema entre ustedes?
是的，我们讨论过。
Yes, we talked about it.
Sí, lo hablamos.
我知道他想去那里。
I knew he wanted to be there.
Yo sabía que él quería estar.
这是一个梦想，但我们认为它是遥不可及的。
And it was a dream, but we saw it as something unattainable.
Y era un sueño, pero lo veíamos como algo inalcanzable.
然后。
then.
en ese momento.
但是，嘿，这是可能的。
But hey, it was possible.
Pero bueno, se pudo.
告诉我你是如何被称呼的，你是如何发现的以及如何......
Tell me how you were called, how you found out and how...
Contame cómo fuiste llamado, cómo te enteraste y cómo...
不知道他们有没有在一起
I don't know if they were together.
No sé si estaban juntos.
没有，我只是在房间里整理宝宝的衣服而已。
No, I was just sorting out the baby's clothes in the room.
No, yo justo estaba ordenando la ropa a la nena en el cuarto.
他独自打开门并告诉我...天哪，他在哭。
And he opens the door alone and tells me... And man, he was crying.
Y abre en sola la puerta y me dice... Y tipo, estaba llorando él.
哭了，我从来没见过他哭成这样。
Crying, I've never seen him cry like that.
Llorando, nunca lo vi llorar así.
哭啊哭，我以为他要告诉我一些悲惨的事情。
Crying, crying and I thought he was going to tell me something tragic.
Llorando, llorando y yo pensé que me iba a decir algo trágico.
我的意思是，有人死了，我不知道。
I mean, someone died, I don't know.
Digo, se murió alguien, no sé.
我就这样做了，他们给我打电话。
And there I did and they called me.
Y ahí me hice y me llamaron.
我的意思是，他们从哪里给你打电话？
I mean, where did they call you from?
Digo, ¿de dónde te llamaron?
在那里他告诉我他们邀请他参加世界杯。
And there he told me that they had called him to be in the World Cup.
Y ahí me dijo que lo habían llamado para estar en el mundial.
是斯卡罗尼本人还是……？
Had it been Scaloni himself or...?
¿Había sido el propio Scaloni o...?
不，我之前就想到过一个。
No, I think one before.
No, creo que una yo antes.
所以他没有停止哭泣，我想他那天晚上没有睡觉。
So he didn't stop crying, he didn't sleep that night, I imagine.
O sea que no paró de llorar, esa noche no habrá dormido, me imagino.
是的，不，我真的很紧张。
Yes, no, I was really nervous.
Sí, no, estaba re nervioso.
所以，是的，这是一种可怕的快乐。
So yes, it was a terrible joy.
Así que sí, fue una alegría terrible.
在那里，你的生活将永远改变。
There your lives change forever.
Ahí cambia la vida de ustedes para siempre.
是的，情况发生了一些变化。
Yes and there it changed a little.
Sí y ahí cambió un poco.
你感觉到了吗？
Do you feel it?
¿Lo sentís?
是的，我想是的。
Yes, I think so.
Sí, yo creo que sí.
前世界和后世界。
before world and post world.
antes mundial y post mundial.
因为？
Because?
¿Por qué?
你有什么感觉？
What do you feel?
¿En qué sentís?
因为它会改变你的一切，包括社交方面。
Because it changes you in everything, socially too.
Porque te cambia en todo, en lo social también.
当他来到阿根廷时，如果他走上街头……
When he comes here to Argentina, if he goes out on the street...
Él cuando viene acá a Argentina, si sale a la calle...
改变事情并说“不”可能会导致广场，这并不是说你做不到，而是你可以做到，但它不会让你成功
change things and saying no can lead to a square, it's not that you can't do it, you can do it but it won't get you
cambia las cosas y decir no puede llevar a una plaza no es que no lo puede hacer lo puede hacer pero no te
你不能拥抱婴儿，因为你将有 30 个人。
You can't cuddle the baby because you're going to have 30 people.
No puedes amacarla a la nena porque vas a tener 30 personas.
30，这很小，因为他们被通知了，发生的事情就是他们被通知了。
30 and it is little, because they are notified, what happens is that they are notified.
30 y es poco, porque se van avisando, pasa eso que se van avisando.
好吧，他们在葡萄牙，那个电话响起，他很高兴，这个新阶段开始了。
Well, they were in Portugal, that call rings, he is happy, this new stage begins.
Bueno, estaban en Portugal, suena ese llamado, se pone contento, empieza esta nueva etapa.
从那时起，距离世界杯还有多久，你还在葡萄牙？
From there, how long until the World Cup and you were still there in Portugal?
¿De ahí cuánto faltaba para el Mundial y ustedes seguían ahí en Portugal?
是的，我们还在葡萄牙，世界杯即将来临，他就离开了。
Yes, we were still in Portugal and the World Cup was just around the corner and he left.
Sí, seguíamos en Portugal y fue el Mundial al toque y él se fue.
告诉我，你把世界杯的一切意义放在一起是什么感觉？
Tell me what it was like for you to put together everything that a World Cup means.
Contame cómo fue para vos armar todo lo que significa un mundial.
嗯，本贾还没到，但和你女儿在一起……
Well, Benja wasn't there yet, but with your daughter...
Ya, bueno, Benja todavía no estaba, pero con tu hija...
家人租了房子陪伴玩家，因为人们不知道如何停下来告诉他们一些
the family rent a house and accompany the player because people don't know how to maybe stop to tell them a little
la familia alquilarse una casa y acompañar al jugador porque la gente no sabe cómo tal vez para para contarles un poco
世界杯期间足球运动员的生活是什么样的？
What is the life of a soccer player like in the middle of the World Cup?
cómo es la vida de un jugador de fútbol en plena, en pleno mundial.
你只能看到它一小会儿。
where you only see it for a little while.
donde solamente lo ves un ratito.
告诉我一些动态。
Tell me a little about the dynamics.
Contame un poco la dinámica.
他们租了一套房子，一家人。
They rented a house, all as a family.
Se alquilaron una casa, todos en familia.
我记得，在不知道他是否处于这种情况的情况下，我去了……
I remember that, not knowing if he was in his condition or not, I went...
Me acuerdo que yo, al no saber si en su estado o no, fui...
最后一次，距离所有人都旅行还有一周，所有其他女性都已经旅行了。
one of the last, it was a week before everyone traveled, all the other women already had.
una de las últimas, fue una semana antes de que viajen todos, todas las demás mujeres ya tenían.
比如酒店、航班。
like the hotel, the flights.
tipo el hotel, los vuelos.
当事情发生时，我开始发现，没有航班。
When it happens and I start to find out, there were no flights.
Cuando pasa y yo empiezo a averiguar, no había vuelos.
没有航班，没有航班，我和奥利维亚独自旅行。
There were no flights, there were no flights and I was traveling alone with Olivia.
No había vuelos, no había vuelos y yo viajaba sola con Olivia.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
我必须去伦敦，中途停留了八个小时
and I had to go to London, I had an eight-hour layover
y tuve que ir a Londres, hice una escala de ocho horas
和她在一起，因为这是那里唯一的东西，然后从那里到卡塔尔
with her because it was the only thing there was and then from there to Qatar
con ella porque era lo único que había y después de ahí a Qatar
孤独。
Lonely.
Solita.
单独和她在一起。
Alone with her.
Sola con ella.
但这是唯一的骗局，没有其他的。
But it was the only hoax there was, there was no other.
Pero era el único bulo que había, no había otro.
显然他已经全神贯注了。
He was already obviously focused.
Él ya estaba obviamente concentrado.
他已经在那里了，是的。
He was already there, yes.
Él ya estaba allá, sí.
你认识球员的妻子吗？
And did you know a player's wife?
¿Y vos conocías a una mujer de algún jugador?
不，那一刻……
No, at that moment...
No, en ese momento...
不，是的，阿玛尼的妻子在那里，我想我是从 River 认识她的。
No, yes, Armani's wife was there, I think I knew her from River.
No, sí, estaba la mujer de Armani, creo que la conocía de River.
然后我就不记得我认识的其他人了。
and then I don't remember what others I knew.
y después no me acuerdo que otras más conocía.
但他们中的大多数人都不知道，我也不认识他们。
but most of them didn't, I didn't know any of them.
pero la mayoría no, no conocía a ninguna.
有什么要说的，你好，我需要这样的东西，我要去吗？
Anything to say, hello, I need something like this, am I going to go something?
¿Algo para decirle, che, hola, necesito tal cosa, voy a ir algo?
不，只是我冒险了。
No, it's just that I took the plunge.
No, es que yo me lancé.
我就这样走了，我试图找到我能做的，仅此而已。
I went like this, I tried to find what I could and that's it.
Fui así, trate de buscar lo que yo podía y listo.
和奥利维亚一起抵达卡塔尔是什么感觉？
With Olivia and what was it like arriving in Qatar?
¿Con Olivia y cómo fue llegar a Qatar?
我们到了，恩佐的父母、我的父亲和恩佐最好的朋友也到了。
We arrived and Enzo's parents, my dad and Enzo's best friend also arrived.
Llegamos y llegaron también los padres de Enzo, mi papá y el mejor amigo de Enzo.
他们都去了那里吗？
And did they all go there?
¿Y ahí se fueron todos?
我们都去了同一个地方。
We all went to the same place.
Fuimos todos al mismo lugar.
是的，我们住在同一家酒店。
Yes, there we were in the same hotel.
Sí, ahí estábamos en el mismo hotel.
而且，这是一种新文化，一切都是新的。
Also, but it was a new culture, everything new.
También, pero era una cultura nueva, todo nuevo.
一切。
Everything.
Todo.
他们每周可以见面一次，这取决于比赛，能否见到他。
And they could meet once a week, and it depends on the game, to be able to see him.
Y se podían una vez a la semana, y depende del partido, poder verlo a él.
当然，他们有家庭日，你可以和他们见面，是的，两三个小时。
Of course, they had family days and you could see them, yes, for two or three hours.
Claro, tenían días de familia y los podías ver, sí, dos o tres horas.
那一刻你对恩佐的感觉如何？
How did you feel about Enzo at that moment?
¿Cómo lo sentiste a Enzo en ese momento?
他用手触摸天空吗？
Was he touching the sky with his hands?
¿Estaba tocando el cielo con las manos?
除此之外，他后来赢得了奖杯。
Beyond that he later won the cup.
Más allá de que después se ganó la copa.
我想那一刻我并没有跌倒在原地。
I think that at that moment it's like I didn't fall where I was.
Yo creo que en ese momento es como que no caía donde estaba.
好吧，他仍然再次享受它。
And well, he still enjoyed it again.
Y bueno, igual lo re-disfrutó.
确实是的。
Yes indeed.
Eso sí.
你感觉如何？
And how did you enjoy it?
¿Y vos cómo lo disfrutaste?
不，我很享受这一边的比赛，但是当谈到点球时我会非常紧张。
No, I enjoyed it on this side, but I get very nervous when it comes to penalties.
No, yo lo disfruté de este lado, pero a mí me dan muchos nervios cuando eres penales.
或者当他们像这样的定义时，“是”或“是”，他们必须获胜。
or when they are like this definitions that yes or yes they have to win.
o cuando son así definiciones que sí o sí tienen que ganar.
你看到他们，他们让你紧张。
You see them, they make you nervous.
Los ves, te ponen nerviosa.
不，不，不，我尽量不去看他们。
No, no, no, I try not to see them.
No, no, no, trato de no verlos.
我要走了，我看到自己离开了球场。
I'm leaving, I saw myself off the court.
Me voy, me vi de la cancha.
啊，你直接过去吧。
Ah, you go directly.
Ah, te vas directamente.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你把自己锁在浴室里，看看会发生什么。
You lock yourself in the bathroom and see what happens.
Te encerras en el baño y ves lo que pasa.
我发誓，他把我锁在浴室里。
I swear, he locked me in the bathroom.
Te juro, me encerraba en el baño.
我把自己和奥利维亚锁在浴室里。
I locked myself and Olivia in the bathroom.
Me encerraba con Olivia en el baño.
人们也开始在粉丝中认出你，明白吗？
And people are also starting to recognize you among the fans, see?
Y la gente empieza a reconocerte también en la hinchada, ¿viste?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
就好像你的伴侣在那一刻看到了它。
It's like your partner is seeing it at that moment.
Es como que lo están viendo a quienes tu pareja en ese momento.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
是的，世界杯结束后，我开始收到很多这样的信息。
Yes, it happens that after the World Cup, I started receiving many messages like that.
Sí, pasa que después del mundial, empecé a recibir muchos mensajes así.
来自人民的喜爱或银行的支持。
of affection from the people or banking us.
de cariño de la gente o bancándonos.
非常有爱。
Much love.
Mucho amor.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
好吧，奖杯赢了。
Well, the cup is won.
Bueno, se gana la copa.
告诉我几个小时前。
Tell me the hours before.
Contame las horas previas.
到那个伟大的日子。
to that great day.
a ese gran día.
你能打电话吗？
Were you able to talk on the phone?
¿Pudiste hablar por teléfono?
他们互相给对方发消息了吗？
Did they send each other a message?
¿Se mandaron un mensaje?
我想是的。
I think so.
Yo creo que sí.
我必须查一下它们，因为我不记得了。
I would have to look them up because I don't remember.
Tendría que buscarlos porque no me acuerdo.
嗯，但是，是的，我们确实谈过，他也一直支持他。
Well, but yes, we sure talked and he always supported him in that.
bien, pero sí, seguro hablamos y siempre en eso lo apoyaba él.
他也总是很积极，就好像他们也很安全一样。
He is also always very positive, it's like they are also safe.
él también siempre muy positivo, es como que igualmente están seguros.
就像整个球队，整个阿根廷一样，有一种良好而积极的氛围，他们将获胜。
Like the whole team, the whole of Argentina, like there was a good and positive vibe that they were going to win.
Como que todo el equipo, toda Argentina, como que había una vibra buena y positiva de que se iba a ganar.
那一刻到来了，奖杯被赢得了，神圣的照片就在那里。
The moment arrives, the cup is won and the divine photos are there.
llega el momento, se gana la copa y están las fotos divinas.
与家人一起，在球场上、在球场上享受。
with family, enjoying in the field, on the court.
en familia, disfrutando en el campo, en la cancha.
那天你还记得什么？
What do you remember about that day?
¿Qué te acordás de ese día?
你还记得什么？
What do you remember?
¿Qué recordás?
疯狂的。
Crazy.
Una locura.
你看到他并拥抱他了吗？
Did you see him and hug him?
¿Lo viste y te abrazaste a él?
你还记得他们说了什么吗？
Do you remember what they said?
¿Te acordás que se dijeron?
是的，我有一个视频，是的。
Yes, I have a video and yes.
Sí, tengo un video y sí.
不，他简直不敢相信。
No, he couldn't believe it.
No, él no lo podía creer.
他哭了吗？
Was he crying?
¿Lloraba?
你是否也像得知此事的那一天一样哭泣？
Did you cry like that day you found out?
¿Lloraba como aquel día que se enteró?
不，我哭了很多次。
No, I cried a lot.
No, lloraba un montón.
他哭了很多次。
He cried a lot.
Lloraba un montón él.
事实是是的。
The truth is yes.
La verdad que sí.
我今天刚给他发了一条消息，我们正在讨论这件事。
I just sent him a message today and we're talking about it.
Hoy justo le mandé un mensaje y estamos hablando de eso.
你给他发了一条消息。
You sent him a message.
Le mandaste un mensaje.
今天是一个非常特别的日子。
Today is a very special day.
Hoy es un día muy particular.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
我要打开一个括号。
I'm going to open a parenthesis.
Voy a abrir un paréntesis.
这是一个非常特别的信息，对于所有阿根廷人来说，自从他们赢得世界杯以来已经过去了两年。
It is a very particular message, two years have passed for all Argentinians since they won this World Cup.
Es un mensaje muy particular, se cumplen para todos los argentinos dos años de haber ganado esta Copa del Mundo.
尽管分开了，你还是给恩佐发了一条消息，说……
And you sent, despite being separated, a message to Enzo that said that...
Y le mandaste, a pesar de estar separados, un mensaje a Enzo que decía que...
今天我们有不同的道路或者我们分开了，但是哦，好吧。
Today we have a different path or we are separated, but oh well.
Hoy tenemos un camino diferente o estamos separados, pero bueno.
我们一起度过了很多时间，我们将继续分享它，所以......
We shared a lot of time together and we are going to continue sharing it so...
compartimos un montón de tiempo juntos y lo vamos a seguir compartiendo así que...
我给他发了一条消息，他也感谢我的到来。
I sent him a message and he thanked me for being there too.
Le mandé un mensaje y él me puso gracias por haber estado también.
你在那条消息里写了什么？
What did you put in that message?
¿Qué le pusiste en ese mensaje?
你有什么感觉？
What did you feel?
¿Qué sentiste?
哦，我很兴奋……是的，但是你觉得怎么样？
Oh, I get excited about... Yes, but what do you think?
Ay, me emociono por... Sí, pero, ¿qué te parece?
我告诉他我喜欢陪伴他。
I told him that I loved having accompanied him.
Le puse que me encantó haberlo acompañado.
和他在一起，帮助他实现他的梦想，并一直在场。
and to have been with him and for him to fulfill his dreams and to have been present there.
y haber estado con él y que él cumpla sus sueños y haber estado yo presente ahí.
什么让你兴奋？
What excites you?
¿Qué te emociona a él?
他们建造的一切，他所完成的一切。
Everything they built, what he accomplished.
Todo lo que construyeron, lo que él logró.
我很兴奋，因为这是他一直想要的东西。
I'm excited that it's something he always wanted.
Me emociona que es algo que él siempre quiso.
或任何球员想要的并且他已经能够实现它并且在那一刻一直陪伴着他并且他
or any player wants and that he has been able to fulfill it and have been accompanying him at that moment and that he
o cualquier jugador quiere y que lo haya podido cumplir y haber estado en ese momento acompañándolo y que él
我也会感受到其中的一部分，是的。
I'm going to feel part of it too, yes.
Me va a sentir parte también, sí.
是的，他做到了，他做到了。
Yes, he did it, he did it.
Sí, que lo logró, que lo haya logrado.
也为了我的孩子们。
and for my children too.
y para mis hijos también.
当时班贾不在场，但对于奥利维亚来说……这将成为她一生的记忆。
Benja wasn't there at the time, but for Olivia... It's going to be a memory of her entire life.
Benja no estaba en ese momento, pero para Olivia... Va a ser un recuerdo de toda su vida.
是的，去过那里，那张照片，我想当他长大后他会看到它。
Yes, having been there, the photo, I think that when he grows up he will see it.
Sí, el haber estado ahí, la foto, yo creo que cuando sea grande lo va a ver.
这就是为什么我喜欢它们是共享的。
That's why I like that they are shared.
Por eso me gusta a mí que sean compartiendo.
和所有。
and all.
y todo.
也是前几天，我们已经分开了，后来被带到法庭，我带了他。
The other day also, we were already separated, it was later taken to the court and I took him.
El otro día también, ya estábamos separados, fue después llevar a la cancha y lo llevé.
当然，还能分享并见到他的父亲。
Of course, and being able to share and see his dad.
Claro, y de poder compartir y verlo a su papá.
当然，我相信他们永远不会忘记那些记忆。
Of course, I believe that they never forget those memories.
Claro, yo creo que esos recuerdos no se los olvidan nunca ellos.
当你在球场上看到那张照片时，看到三人组和奖杯......
When you see that photo on the field and there are the three and the cup...
Cuando ves esa foto en la cancha y están los tres y la copa...
这是一张随处可见的照片。
and it is a photo that was everywhere.
y es una foto que estuvo en todos lados.
我想它会来到圣马丁社区 Mar del Tuchú
I imagine that it is coming to the San Martín neighborhood, Mar del Tuchú
te imagino que se viene en el barrio San Martín, Mar del Tuchú
有时候你并不相信事实。
There are times when you don't fall for what it is.
Es que hay veces que no caes por lo que es.
伙计，你说，我离开这里，今天你就拥有了一切。
Guy, you say, I left here and today you have everything.
tipo, decís, salí de acá y hoy tenés todo.
但好吧，就像我说的那样。
But well, it's like I say too.
Pero bueno, es como que yo también digo.
我总是这样告诉他。
I always told him that.
Yo siempre, yo se lo decía a él.
一旦我们回来，对我来说你不是世界冠军，对我来说你是恩佐。
Once we get back, to me you are not world champion, to me you are Enzo.
Una vez que volvamos, para mí no sos campeón del mundo, para mí sos Enzo.
你明白，所以这就像是的，但我并不像其他人那样看待它。
You understand, so it's like yes, but I didn't see it the way other people see it.
Entendés, entonces es como que sí, pero no lo veía como lo ve las demás personas.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
他成为世界冠军的那一天，对我们来说也改变了所有阿根廷人。
the day he became world champion and that for us also changed all Argentinians.
el día que se convierte en campeón del mundo y que para nosotros también nos cambió a todos los argentinos.
而这种喜悦，回家是什么感觉？
And this joy, what was it like to return home?
Y esta alegría, ¿cómo fue volver a casa?
和奥利维亚一起，和他在一起，并且知道他赢得了那个奖杯。
With Olivia, with him, and knowing that he had won that cup.
Con Olivia, con él, y sabiendo que se había ganado esa copa.
不，太高兴了，我记得我们是乘坐直达飞机旅行的
No, a terrible joy, I remember that we traveled on a direct plane
No, una alegría terrible, me acuerdo que viajamos en un avión directo
从卡塔尔到阿根廷。
from Qatar to Argentina.
de Qatar a Argentina.
他踩刹车加油了一次，但已经连续 22 个小时了。
He braked once to fill up on gas but it was 22 straight hours.
Frenó una vez para cargar nafta pero eran 22 horas seguidas.
的受害者。
of the victims.
de las víctimas.
满员玩家？
Full of players?
¿lleno de jugadores?
不，不，不是球员，而是所有的家人都在那里。
No, no, not the players, but all the families were there.
No, no, los jugadores no, pero estábamos todas las familias.
所有的家庭，包括妇女，都在场。
All the families were there, the women.
Estaban todas las familias, las mujeres.
女人，所有的孩子，是的。
The women, all the children, yes.
Las mujeres, todos los hijos, sí.
嗯，这真是令人兴奋。
Well, so it was a thrill.
Bueno, así que era una emoción.
糟糕的。
Terrible.
球员们都单向前进，必须组成一个著名的集体……
and the players, who all went one way, had to make the famous collective that...
y los jugadores, que se iban todos por un lado, tenían que hacer el famoso colectivo que...
你是怎么遵循的？
How did you follow it?
¿Cómo lo seguiste vos?
因为我们都看着他以及正在发生的所有事情。
Because we all looked at him with all the things that were happening.
Porque si todos lo mirábamos con todas las cosas que pasaban.
他们，都中暑了，喝酒了。
They, all sunstroke, drinking.
Ellos, todos insolados, tomando.
你是如何体验的？
How did you experience it?
¿Cómo lo viviste vos?
当时你在哪里？
Where were you?
¿Dónde estabas?
它怎么样？
How was it?
¿Cómo fue?
不，难以置信。
No, incredible.
No, increíble.
但看到它仍然令人难以置信，因为我在电视上看到了它。
But it was still incredible to see it because I saw it on TV.
Pero igual era increíble verlo porque lo vi de la tele.
我不能去。
I couldn't go.
No podía ir.
不，不是我不能去，我可以去，但这太疯狂了。
No, it wasn't that I couldn't go, I could go, but it was crazy.
No, no era que no podía ir, podía ir, pero era una locura.
那么你是如何遵循的呢？
So how did you follow it?
Por eso, ¿cómo lo seguiste?
在你的房子里。
in your house.
en tu casa.
是的，我当时在我家，然后恩佐来了，你中暑了，我记得。
Yes, I was at my house and then Enzo arrived, your sunstroke, I remember.
Sí, yo estaba en mi casa y después llegó Enzo tu insolado, me acuerdo.
是的，太可怕了。
Yes, terrible.
Sí, terrible.
当你在电视上看到它并拒绝时，你是否感到痛苦？
And did you suffer when you saw it on TV and said no?
¿Y sufrías cuando veías en la tele y decías no?
不，是的，他们疯了，他们疯了。
No, yes they were crazy, they were crazy.
No, sí estaban chochos, estaban chochos ellos.
但有时他们必须下车，你看，有时你会担心，你说，好吧，他们要把我们送上公共汽车。
But at one point they had to get off, you see, sometimes you get worried and you say, well, they were putting us on the bus.
pero en un momento se tuvieron que bajar, viste, que a veces uno se preocupa y decís, bueno, nos iban subiendo al colectivito.
不，不，他们疯了。
No, no, they are crazy.
No, no, ellos están chochos.
那么冠军的生活如何继续呢？
And then how does the life of a champion continue?
¿Y después cómo sigue la vida de un campeón?
不，然后就像你上去一样，但是我说，等一切平静下来之后，你可以再往下走，到地面去。
No, and then it's like you go up, but I say, after everything calms down more, you can go down further to the ground.
No, y después es como que subís, pero yo digo, ya después ya se aplaca más todo, podés bajar más a tierra.
所以，没什么，在他去英国之后，我们就离开了。
So, nothing, after he left for England, we left.
Así que, nada, después él se fue para Inglaterra, nos fuimos.
他对它们进行测试。
He puts them to the test.
Se le pone al tempito.
是的，他在一月底离开了。
Yes, he left at the end of January.
Sí, él se fue en fines de enero.
所以一切都在那里。
So it was all there.
O sea que fue todo ahí.
一切都很快。
Everything fast.
Todo rápido.
一切都在那里。
Everything there.
Todo ahí.
当我看到你情绪激动时，我称你为牺牲和生命。
When I see you get emotional and I name you sacrifice and life.
Cuando te veo que te emocionás y yo te nombro el sacrificio y la vida.
好吧，我想你作为一名孕妇，也看不到国外的生活。
Okay, I imagine that you, as a pregnant woman, don't see a life abroad either.
Vale, me imagino que uno tampoco ve, vos como mujer embarazada, una vida en el exterior.
一切看起来都很美好，你会说，哦，玩家琥珀的生命是多么神圣啊！
Everything seems rosy and you say, oh, how divine the life of a player's amber!
todo parece color de rosa y dices, ¡ay, qué divina la vida del ámbar de un jugador!
它有很多牺牲，也有很多看不见的东西。
It has a lot of sacrifices and a lot of things that are not seen.
Tiene un montón de sacrificios y un montón de cosas que no se ven.
是的，是的，确实如此。
Yes, yes, that's true.
Sí, sí, eso es verdad.
有很多东西是看不见的，但是……
There are a lot of things that are not seen, but...
Hay un montón de cosas que no se ven, pero...
幸运的是，它有其优点和缺点。
Luckily it kind of has its pros and cons.
Por suerte es como que tiene sus pros y sus contras.
告诉我优点和缺点。
Tell me the pros and cons.
Contame los pros y los contras.
作为？
As?
¿Cómo?
关于什么？
About what?
¿De qué?
您最触手可及的探头。
The probes that you have the most within reach.
Los probes que tenés más en el alcance.
我看到有人也有同样的情况，他们独自和家人在一起。
I see that there are people who are also in the same situation, who are alone with their family.
Yo veo que hay gente que también está en la misma situación, que está sola con la familia.
除了有能力之外，一切都需要花费他们去医院的费用，或者另一方面，这是经济的 是 是
everything but capable costs them for a hospital or on the other hand that is economical yes yes
todo pero capaz les cuesta para un hospital o de lado ese lo económico sí sí
他们为你解决问题，但同时，例如，在分娩期间，你可以在最好的医院，但你是孤独的。
They solve things for you but at the same time, for example, during childbirth, you can be in the best hospital but you are alone.
te solucionan las cosas pero igual al momento por ejemplo del parto podes estar en el mejor hospital pero estas sola
还。
Also.
También.
幸运的是，我碰巧参加了家庭旅行。
Luckily it happened to me that I made part of my family travel.
A mí pasó por suerte que hice viajar a parte de mi familia.
陪伴，因为他也受过这方面的训练，他出生为venja，不得不离开
to be accompanied because he also trained in that, he was born venja and had to leave
para estar acompañada porque en eso también entrenaba tipo él nació venja y se tuvo que ir
那么... Venja 出生在哪里？
So... Venja was born where?
Así que... ¿Venja nació dónde?
在英国。
In England.
En Inglaterra.
Venja 出生在英国吗？
Was Venja born in England?
¿Venja nace en Inglaterra?
我告诉他，他是我的英国男孩。
He's my English boy, I tell him.
Es mi niño inglés, le digo yo.
你看到你儿子惹怒了什么。
You saw what your son is causing a fury.
Vos viste lo que causa furor tu hijo.
现在他们告诉我，他已经到了Caixa，是个邻里男孩。
Now they tell me that he has already arrived at Caixa and is a neighborhood boy.
Ahora me dicen que ya llegó a Caixa y es un nene de barrio.
没人关心Caixa，她只想要你的儿子。
Nobody cared about Caixa, she only wanted your son.
A Caixa no le importabas a nadie, solamente quería a tu hijo.
你没有遵守，所以在 2025 年你带来了它。
that you didn't comply so in 2025 you bring it.
que no cumpliste así que en el 2025 lo traes.
不，我要带它。
No, I'm going to bring it.
No, lo voy a traer.
在某个时刻。
At some point.
En algún momento.
我是这么想的，怎么样？
I thought that, how was it?
Eso pensaba, ¿cómo fue?
有什么不同吗？
Was it different?
¿Fue distinto?
奥利维亚出生时，恩佐与班贾出生时的恩佐不同。
When Olivia was born, Enzo was not the same Enzo as when Benja was born.
Cuando nació Olivia, Enzo no era el mismo Enzo que cuando nació Benja.
当奥利维亚出生时，我把她带到了一家诊所，在那里我有一个社会工作项目。
When Olivia was born I had her here in a clinic, where I had a social project for work.
Cuando nace Olivia la tuve acá en una clínica, que yo tenía una obra social por el trabajo.
这是一家与其他……与其他女性共用一个房间的诊所。
It was a clinic that shared a room with other... With other women.
Era una clínica que compartía cuarto con otras... Con otras mujeres.
我像任何人一样正常生活。
I live normal, like any person.
Tivo normal, como cualquier persona.
这是不知道的吗？
Was that not known?
¿Eso no era conocido?
这是不知道的，是吗？
That wasn't known, was it?
Eso no era conocido, ¿no?
好吧，这只是一场流行病。
Well, it was just a pandemic.
Bueno, era justo pandemia.
是的，我的情况有所不同。
Yes, I had it different.
Sí, la tuve diferente.
他们是其他人...
They were others...
Eran otras...
我记得当时，我不知道，我的家人就像他们帮我买尿布，我们给Uli买衣服。
I remember that at that time, I don't know, my family was like they helped me buy diapers, we bought clothes for Uli.
Me acuerdo que en ese momento, no sé, mi familia era como que me ayudaban a comprar los pañales, a Uli le comprábamos ropa
暂停
paused
pausada.
这就是我记得从你那里听到的，你的女儿
That's what I remember hearing from you that your daughter
Eso me acuerdo de haberte escuchado que a tu hija
当然，它们是两种不同的东西，但所发生的情况是，一个有四个，另一个有一个，然后……
Sure, they were two different things, but what happens is that one has four and another one and in that...
Claro, fueron dos cosas diferentes, pero lo que pasa es que una tiene cuatro y otro uno y en ese...
发生了很多事情。
a lot of things happened.
medio pasaron un montón de cosas.
它改变了你们俩的生活吗？
Did it change both of your lives?
¿Les cambió la vida a los dos?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你本来可以陪着他。
You could have accompanied him.
A vos poder haberlo acompañado.
并把赌注押在历史和他成为的人身上。
and having bet on history and who he became.
y haber apostado a la historia y a él por quien se convirtió.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
我们正在谈论您的女儿，甚至使用您为她买的衣服以及为取得成功而做出的所有牺牲。
We were talking about your daughter, even used clothes that you bought for her and all the sacrifice to get ahead.
Hablábamos de tu hija, hasta ropa usada que le comprabas y todo un sacrificio de salir adelante.
Benja 的出生是什么样的？
And what was Benja's birth like?
¿Y cómo fue el nacimiento de Benja?
本贾在萨拉达出生。
The birth of Benja in Sallada.
El nacimiento de Benja en Sallada.
他已经在切尔西了，他也已经有了另一个财务职位。
He is already at Chelsea, he already had another financial position as well.
ya está en el Chelsea, ya tenía otra posición económica también.
可以说，我们也更成熟了一些。
We were also a little more adults so to speak.
Nosotros también estábamos un poco más adultos por decirlo.
但不一样了，从19岁开始就变了，因为我已经有了一个女儿，我已经有了更多的知识。
But it is not the same, from 19 it changes because I already had a daughter, I already had more knowledge.
Pero no es lo mismo, de 19 va cambiando porque yo ya estaba con una hija, ya tenía más conocimientos.
我们就像是更加武装起来，作为一个家庭也是如此。
We were like we were more armed, also as a family.
Éramos como en que estábamos más armados, también como familia.
您什么时候进行剖腹产或自然分娩？
When did you have a cesarean section or natural birth?
¿Cuándo tuviste cesárea o parta natural?
不，顺其自然吧。
No, go natural.
No, parta natural.
两者都有吗？
With both?
¿Con los dos?
是的，两者都有。
Yes, with both.
Sí, con los dos.
你告诉我，当奥利出生时，他显然留下来陪伴着你。
You told me that when Oli was born, he was, obviously, he stayed and accompanied you.
Me decías que cuando nació Oli, él estaba, obviamente, se quedó y te acompañó.
本杰怎么了？
What happened to Benja?
¿Qué pasó con Benja?
你的羊水破裂了吗？
Did your water break and it was there?
¿Rompiste bolsa y estaba?
不，发生在我身上的是我拥有更多
No, what happened to me is that I had more
No, a mí lo que me pasó es que tenía más
袋子里的液体比平常多，所以是自然分娩，但它是预定的，因为
liquid in the bag than normal so it was a natural birth but it was scheduled because
líquido en la bolsa de lo normal así que fue un parto fue natural pero fue programado porque
是的，他出生时已经38周了，但他不必放弃那么多。
Yes, he was born at 38 weeks, but he didn't have to let that much go.
Sí, nació a las 38 semanas, pero no tenía que dejar pasar tanto.
那么他可以陪你吗？
And could he accompany you?
¿Y él te pudo acompañar?
是的，他陪着你，他在孩子出生的时候，但是第二天……
Yes, he accompanied you, he was at the birth of the baby, but the next day...
Sí Te acompañó, estuvo en el parto del bebé, pero al otro día...
那天晚上他陪着我，因为我晚上10点才可以上网。
He accompanied me that night, because I had internet at 10 at night.
Me acompaño esa noche, porque a mí internet a las 10 de la noche.
我们整个晚上都在那里，他应该是在晚上出生的，但他整天都在那里，我们整个早上都和恩佐在一起，只有我们两个人。
We were there all night, he was supposed to have been born at night and he was there all day, we were there all morning with Enzo and we were just the two of us.
Estuvimos toda la noche, supuestamente tendía que haber nacido a la noche y estuvo todo el día, estuvimos toda la madrugada con Enzo y estábamos los dos solos.
第二天他就去训练了，因为他死了。
and the next day he went to train because he was dead.
y al otro día eso se fue a entrenar que estaba muerto.
他们在切尔西为他拍了一张照片，看起来像……
There's a photo they took of him from Chelsea that looked like...
Hay una foto que le sacaron del Chelsea que estaba como que...
他24小时没有睡觉。
He didn't sleep for 24 hours.
No durmió por 24 horas.
Benja 是什么时候出生的？
And what time was Benja born?
¿Y Benja qué hora nació?
他是下午一点出生的。
He was born at one in the afternoon.
Nació a la una de la tarde.
他去训练然后到达了？
And he went to train and arrived?
¿Y se fue a entrenar y llegó?
不，他后来去训练了。
No, he went to train later.
No, se fue a entrenar después.
啊，太完美了，本克出生了，然后他就去训练了。
Ah, perfect, Benke was born and then he went to train.
Ah, perfecto, nació Benke y después se fue a entrenar.
换句话说，就是你和宝宝在一起的最初几个小时。
In other words, the first few hours you stay with the baby.
O sea que las primeras horas una se queda con el bebé.
我的意思是，还有另一件，然后衬衫到了。
I mean, and the other one, then the shirt arrived.
Digo, y el otro, después llegó la camisa.
不，这就是为什么，直到那天晚上晚些时候，伊曼·科马内霍（Iman Comanejo）才不得不回去训练和做其他事情。
No, that's why, until Iman Comanejo later that night he had to go back to training and everything.
No, por eso, hasta Iman Comanejo después a la noche él ya tenía que volver a entrenar y todo.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
也许这与你所说的有点相反。
That's a bit of the opposite of what you name, perhaps.
Eso es un poco lo contra que nombras, tal vez.
一开始需要的三四天。
those three or four days that one needs at the beginning.
esos tres o cuatro días que uno necesita al principio.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
好吧，生命就在那里，而且……
Well, life is there and...
Bueno, queda la vida ahí y...
现在最后的目的地还是这个。
Now the last destination was still this.
Ahora el último destino seguía siendo este.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
我一直这样做，几个月前这是这个新闻，因为......
I kept doing this and a few months ago it was this news because...
Seguía haciendo este y hace algunos meses fue esta noticia porque...
事实是，这就是发生在你身上的事情，你没有撒谎，你们分开了。
The truth is that it was what had happened to you and you didn't lie, you separated.
la verdad que era lo que te había sucedido y no mentiste, te separaste.
到底发生了什么？
What was it that happened?
¿Qué fue lo que pasó?
不，这不是特别发生的，我总是听到的，然后没有说出来。
No, it didn't particularly happen, I always heard it and didn't say it then.
No, particularmente no pasó, yo siempre lo oí y entonces no lo dije.
之前什么都没发生。
Nothing happened before.
Antes no pasó nada.
我认为他有能力做很多事情。
I think he was capable of a set of things.
Yo creo que fue capaz un conjunto de cosas.
就他而言，他做出了决定，我尊重他的决定。
On his part, he made the decision and I respected it.
de parte de él, él tomó la decisión y yo se la respeté.
我们有两个共同的孩子，我告诉他今天我们努力建立良好的关系，以便我们可以分享
We have two children in common, I told him to this day we try to have a good relationship so that we can share that the
tenemos dos hijos en común yo le dije hasta el día de hoy tratamos de tener una buena relación de que podamos compartir de que los
他们可以继续看到我们在一起。
They can continue seeing us together.
nos puedan seguir viendo juntos.
没有什么特别的事情发生，如果你问我发生了什么，我没有什么特别的事情可以告诉你。
Nothing in particular happened, if you ask me what happened, I have nothing in particular to tell you.
No pasó nada en particular, si vos me preguntás qué pasó, no tengo nada para decirte en particular.
只是我认为埃洛伊的决定更多。
It's just that I think Eloy decides more.
solamente que yo creo que Eloy decide más.
100%专注于你的事业，专注于表现，专注于寻找自己，有能力的人没有找到。
Focus 100% on your career, on performing, on looking for yourself, the capable one was not found.
enfocarse 100% en su carrera, en rendir, en buscarse, el capaz no se encontraba.
在他作为球员的最佳时刻，我努力寻找它。
in his best moment as a player and I try to look for it.
en su mejor momento como jugador y trato de buscarlo.
今天幸运的是他表现得很好所以没有因此我也很高兴
Today luckily he is doing well so nothing for that reason I am also happy
hoy por suerte le está yendo bien así que nada por eso también estoy contenta
但是两个月前这个消息发生的时候，你说他来告诉你他需要一个空间。
But when this news happened two months ago, you said that he came and told you that he needed a space.
Pero cuando sucede esta noticia hace dos meses, que vos contaste que él vino y te dijo que necesitaba un espacio.
并分开。
and separate.
y separarse.
你是否感到惊讶或者你是否意识到这段关系没有进展？
Were you surprised or did you realize that the relationship was not going?
¿A vos te sorprendió o ahí te diste cuenta que la relación no iba?
不，这让我很惊讶，但是……
No, it surprised me, but...
No, a mí me sorprendió, pero...
不，不，惊讶并不奇怪。
No, no, surprising was not surprising.
No, no, sorprender no sorprendió.
是的，我不会在这方面对你撒谎。
Yes, I'm not going to lie to you about that.
Sí, eso no te voy a mentir.
但也就像我说的，嗯，这就是他想要的。
But it's also like I said, well, that's what he wants.
Pero también es como que dije, bueno, ya está lo que él quiere.
我不会束缚自己，我不会留下来。
I'm not going to tie myself down, I'm not going to stay.
No me voy a atar, no me voy a quedar.
这是你的决定。
It's your decision.
Es su decisión.
但你想象一下洗碗的时候另一个人过来告诉你……一天又一天就是这样，是的。
But you imagine washing the dishes and the other person comes and tells you... That's how it was one day to the next, yes.
Pero uno se imagina lavando los platos y que venga el otro y te diga... Así fue un día para el otro, sí.
是的，是的，就是这样。
Yes, yes, it was like that.
Sí, sí, fue así.
他们在哪里？
Where were they?
¿Dónde estaban?
她刚玩完游戏，我就去找她了。
I had gone to look for her just as she had finished playing a game.
Yo la había ido a buscar justo que terminaba de jugar un partido.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
他从机场下来，我去找他，我们在那里聊了聊，当时我们就聊了。
And he had come down from the airport and I went to look for him and there we had a talk and we talked at that moment.
Y había bajado del aeropuerto y lo fui a buscar y ahí tuvimos una charla y hablamos en ese momento.
但你在去机场的路上想着我们今晚要吃饭。
But you went on the way to the airport thinking we're eating tonight.
Pero vos fuiste camino al aeropuerto pensando que comemos esta noche.
当然，有这样的氛围。
Sure, a vibe like that.
Claro, una onda así.
就这样的一波。
A wave like that.
Una onda así.
当他在车上告诉你的时候。
When he tells you in the car.
Cuando él te dice en el auto.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
¿Qué te pasó?
你的身体怎么了？
What happened to your body?
¿Qué se te pasó por el cuerpo?
不，没什么，我说，好吧……不，不，没有那个我很平静。
No, nothing, I said, well... No, no, without that I'm very calm.
No, nada, dije, bueno... No, no, yo sin eso soy muy tranquila.
我告诉他，好吧，我接受他所做的决定，这很好。
I told him, well, it's fine that I accepted the decision he made.
Le dije, bueno está bien que aceptaba la decisión que él tomara.
他的决定是留在英格兰，然后返回阿根廷。
His decision was to stay in England, return to Argentina.
Su decisión era quedate en Inglaterra, volvete a Argentina.
我想这是他对男孩们的恐惧。
It was his fear of the boys, I imagine.
Era su miedo los chicos, me imagino.
是的，他告诉我，我确实愿意，我可以住在我们住的房子里。
Yes, he told me that I did want to, I could stay in the house where we lived.
Sí, él me planteó que yo sí quería, me podía quedar en la casa donde nosotros vivíamos.
他打算租别的东西，但我是决定来这里的。
and that he was going to rent something else, but I was the one who decided to come here.
y que él se iba a alquilar otra cosa, pero yo fui la que decidí venirme acá.
你有没有考虑过这一点，或者你是否拒绝了？
Did you think about that a little or did you say no?
¿Eso lo pensaste un poco o dijiste no?
不，直接。
No, directly.
No, directamente.
你有什么清楚的吗？
Do you have something clear?
¿Tienes algo claro?
我告诉过你，我因为你才住在这里。
I told you, I live here because of you.
Yo se lo dije, yo vivo acá por vos.
如果由我决定的话，我不会住在这里。
If it were up to me, I wouldn't live here.
Si fuera por mí, no viviría acá.
我会和我的家人住在一起。
I would live with my family.
Viviría con mi familia.
还有我也...
And me too...
Y yo también...
这些年来，我不再与家人、兄弟分享时光。
All those years I stopped sharing moments with my family, my brothers.
todos esos años dejé de compartir momentos con mi familia, mis hermanos.
所以我更愿意来这里让他们也和他们的表兄弟在一起。
So I preferred to come here and have them also be with their cousins.
Así que preferí venir acá y que ellos también estén con sus primos.
当他对你说，我做出这个决定的那一刻，你们在一起生活了多久？
The moment he talks to you and says, I made this decision, how much longer did you live together?
El momento en que él te habla y dice, tomé esta decisión, ¿cuánto tiempo más vivieron juntos?
十天。
Ten days.
Diez días.
那10天是什么样的呢？
And what were those 10 days like?
¿Y cómo fueron esos 10 días?
不，嗯，正常。
No, well, normal.
No, re bien, normal.
他是一个非常特别的亲爱的人，他是神圣的，我祝贺你，美丽的。
He is a very special dear personality, he is divine, I congratulate you, beautiful.
Es una personalidad querida muy especial, es divino, yo te felicito, hermoso.
不，那十天很好，我们还在一起拍照，什么都有。
No, those ten days were fine, we even have photos together, everything.
No, esos diez días bien, hasta tenemos fotos juntos, todo.
他们睡在一起了吗？
Did they sleep together?
¿Dormían juntos?
他们做爱了吗？
Did they make love?
¿Hicieron el amor?
是的，有些人在今天中午说是的。
Yes, some said yes, in the middle of this day.
Sí, algunos dijeron sí, en el medio de este día.
噢，告别？
Oh, farewell?
¿Ah, de despedida?
他们说再见了吗？
Did they say this goodbye?
¿Se dijeron esto de despedida?
你说实际上他也需要，不仅是职业上的，而且是生活上的。
You said that in reality he needed as well, not only professionally, but to live.
Vos contaste que en realidad él necesitaba como también, no solamente lo profesional, pero vivir.
好的...
Good...
Buen...
关于其他事情，因为他们非常年轻。
about other things because they were, like, very young.
de otras cosas porque eran como muy chicos.
是的，就像我告诉你的那样，我告诉你的一切都发生在一段时间内......
Yes, like I told you, everything I told you happened in a period of...
Sí, como te dije, todo lo que te conté pasó en un lapso de...
两年、三年。
two, three years.
dos, tres años.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
这对他来说也意义重大。
It was a lot for him too.
Fue mucho para él también.
对你来说呢？
And for you?
¿Y para vos?
对我来说也是如此。
And for me too.
Y para mí también.
问题是，我想我当时...
The thing is, I think I was...
Lo que pasa es que yo creo que lo fui...
我用另一种方式引导它。
I was channeling it in another way.
lo fui canalizando de otra manera.
我是陪着的。
I was accompanied.
Yo estaba acompañada.
我一直很感激的是去那里和我女儿住在一起。
Something I am always grateful for is having gone there to live with my daughter.
Yo algo que agradezco siempre es haber ido allá a vivir con mi hija.
因为我认为当你一个人去的时候会困难得多。
because I think it's much more difficult when you go alone.
porque yo creo que es mucho más difícil cuando te vas sola.
当女人独自离开时，情况会更糟，因为我有东西，我带她去学校，我和她一起去看比赛。
When women leave alone it is worse because I had something and I took her to school, I went to the games with her.
Cuando las mujeres se van solas es peor porque yo tenía algo y la llevaba al colegio, iba a los juegos con ella.
所以好像我也不孤单。
So it was like I wasn't alone either.
Entonces era como que no estaba tampoco sola sola.
你被逗乐了。
You were entertained.
Estabas entretenida.
我和家人在一起。
I was with my family.
Estaba con mi familia.
当然，你有事情要做。
Sure, you had things to do.
Claro, tenías cosas para hacer.
10天后你就来了。
You came after 10 days.
Te viniste a los 10 días.
你怎么告诉你父母的？
How did you tell your parents?
¿Cómo le contaste a tus viejos?
我要回阿根廷生活。
I'm going back to Argentina to live.
se me vuelve a Argentina a vivir.
我爸爸当时就在那里。
My dad was just there.
Mi papá justo estaba allá.
啊，真幸运。
Ah, how lucky.
Ah, qué suerte.
因为我爸爸来参加本杰明的生日，所以...
Because my dad came for Benjamin's birthday, so...
Porque mi papá vino por el cumpleaños de Benjamín, así que...
是的，本卡的生日刚刚过半，我也已经付清了所有的费用。
Yes, Benka's birthday just happened in the middle and I also already had everything paid for, everything.
Sí, justo pasó el cumpleaños de Benka en el medio y yo ya tenía también todo pago, todo.
我说，好吧，不。
And I said, well, no.
Y dije, bueno, no.
我们留下来庆祝我们的生日，这是我们在一起的第一年，然后我离开了。
We stayed celebrating our birthday, it was our first year together and then I left.
Nos quedamos festejando el cumpleaños, era el primer año juntos y después me voy.
所以当你告诉你爸爸的时候，你就有了你的爸爸。
So you had your dad when you told your dad.
O sea que tenías a tu papá cuando le contás a tu papá.
不，我告诉我爸爸。
No, I told my dad.
No, a mi papá le conté.
我父亲刚刚去了西班牙，那是在西班牙的家庭日。
My dad had just gone to Spain, that family day in Spain.
Mi papá justo se había ido a España, aquel día de familia en España.
知道要去拜访他们，这就是他同时告诉我的。
knew to visit them and that's what he told me in the meantime.
sabido visitarlos y eso me dijo en ese interin.
当我爸爸回来时，我没有对他说什么，我告诉他要听，但不要发表意见。
And when my dad came back I didn't say anything to him, I told him to listen, but not to give an opinion.
Y cuando volvió mi papá nada le dije, le dije que escuche, pero que no opine.
原来我只听自己的。
That I only listened to myself.
Que solamente me escuché.
不不不，事情就是这样。
No, no, that's how it was.
No, no, así fue.
他说，好吧。
And he said, well.
Y me dijo, bueno.
想象一下我父亲和恩佐继续分享。
Imagine that my dad and Enzo continued sharing.
Imagínate que mi papá y Enzo siguieron compartiendo.
直到今天，他们说的都是一样的。
To this day they speak the same.
Hasta hoy se hablan igual.
但我也想，那就是我要住的地方。
But that's where I'm going to live, I imagine too.
Pero ahí era donde voy a vivir, me imagino también.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
是的，就是这样。
Yes, that was it.
Sí, fue todo.
十天之内，他把所有的东西都整理好了。
In ten days he put everything together.
En diez días armó todo.
不，十天内一切都毁了。
No, in ten days everything was ruined.
No, en diez días se arruinó todo.
所以，十天内你拼凑的东西，你必须拼凑起来。
Therefore, in ten days what you put together, you had to put it together.
Por eso, en diez días qué armaste, había que armar.
手提箱，搬家，带着两个男孩，看看我们住的地方。
The suitcase, the move, bringing the two boys, seeing where we live.
La valija, la mudanza, traer a los dos chicos, ver a dónde vivimos.
10天之内，是的，我收拾了行李箱，我在那里的时候收拾了行李箱，盒子......
In 10 days, yes, I packed suitcases, I packed the suitcases while I was there, boxes...
En 10 días sí, armé valijas, fui armando las valijas mientras estaba ahí, cajas...
如果我组装的话，想象一下 50 个盒子。
If I assembled, imagine 50 boxes.
si armé imaginate 50 cajas
中间有没有谈过，好吧？
Did you talk about it, OK, in the middle or not?
¿Lo hablabas, Vale, en el medio o no?
不，我在听……但是为什么……
No, I was listening... But why...
No, estaba escuchando... Pero porque...
我想我没有哭，因为那不是我的事。
I think I didn't cry because it wasn't my thing.
Creo que no lo lloré porque no fue algo mío.
这是别人的决定。
It was someone else's decision.
Fue una decisión del otro.
我已经无能为力了。
I can't do anything anymore.
Yo ya no puedo hacer más nada.
就好像有一个屏障，类型，它可以走到这里。
It's like there is a barrier, type, it can go up to here.
Es como que hay una barrera, tipo, hasta acá puede llegar.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
还有更多，对吧？
More of that, right?
Más de eso, ¿no?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
我无法深入思考并告诉第六个。
I can't go into the head and tell the sixth.
No puedo entrar a la cabeza y decirle a la sexto.
所以没什么，我会和恩佐一起做。
So nothing, I would do it with Enzo.
Así que nada, lo haría con Enzo.
今天他是恩佐，如果他是其他人，明天他也会对其他人做同样的事情。
Today he is Enzo and if he were someone else, tomorrow he would do the same with someone else.
Hoy es Enzo y si fuera otra persona el día de mañana lo haría igual con otra persona.
今天你爱上他了吗？
Are you in love with him today?
¿Hoy estás enamorada de él?
我认为有很多事情......我不知道如何解释。
And I think there are a lot of things... I don't know how to explain it.
Y yo creo que hay un montón de cosas... No sé cómo explicarlo.
显然，从布局等方面来看，有很多东西，是的，有些东西被破坏了，但是......
There are a lot of things that, obviously, from the layout and so on, yes, something was broken, but...
Hay un montón de cosas que, obvio, del planteo y demás, sí, se quebró algo, pero...
但我确实喜欢它，而且我会一直在那里。
But I do love it and I will be there, always.
Pero sí que lo quiero y voy a estar, eso sí, siempre.
他知道这一点。
And he knows it.
Y él lo sabe.
它仍然让你兴奋。
It still excites you.
Te emociona todavía.
不，有时是的。
No, there are times that yes.
No, hay veces que sí.
不，显然有时它确实让我兴奋。
No, obviously there are times when it does excite me.
No, obvio que hay veces que sí me emociona.
我一直这么说。
I always said it.
Yo siempre lo dije.
我谈到了这一点，我更多的是关于我的孩子，或者很少见到他们，而且......
And I talked about it with that, I was more about my children, or seeing them so little and that...
y lo hablé con eso, yo era más por mis hijos, o ver tan chiquitos y que...
很多事情，比如父亲，不幸的是他会想念他们，但不是因为他不想，而是距离本身阻止了它。
a lot of things, like a dad, unfortunately he is going to miss them, but not because he doesn't want to, but rather the distance itself prevents it.
un montón de cosas, él como un papá lamentablemente se las va a perder, pero no porque él no quiera, sino la misma distancia lo impide.
但...
But...
Pero...
你是否觉得他无法承受这一切却仍然爱着你？
Do you feel like he couldn't handle all this and is still in love with you?
¿Sentís que él no pudo manejar todo esto y sigue enamorado de vos?
不，我不知道。
No, I don't know that.
No, eso no lo sé.
说实话，我走后，我们就不再谈论自己作为情侣了。
Honestly, after I left, we didn't talk about ourselves as a couple anymore.
Sinceramente, yo después de que me fui, nosotros no hablamos más de nosotros como pareja.
我们只谈论孩子和其他人以及日常生活
We only talk about the kids and others and day to day
solamente hablamos por los nenes y demás y el día a día
他们可以问我怎么样，是否需要什么，但不，这是一个关系问题，我们不再谈论它。
They can ask how I am, if I need anything, but no, it's a relationship issue, we don't talk about it anymore.
pueden preguntar cómo estoy, si necesito algo, pero no, tipo tema de relación, no lo hablamos más.
当你回到阿根廷时，最初的几天很困难，除了你的性格......
When you returned to Argentina, the first few days were difficult beyond the fact that you have a personality that...
Cuando volviste a la Argentina fue difícil los primeros días más allá de que tenés una personalidad que...
你可以努力做到，而我...不，这并不难，因为这一切都非常...
You can do it hard and I... No, it wasn't difficult because it was all very...
que te la bancas y fuerte y yo... No, no fue difícil porque fue todo como muy...
一切都很美丽，可以说。
All beautifully, let's say.
Todo de forma linda, digamos.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
我表弟来了这里，头几天她和我在一起，我和我的祖母都在看。
My cousin came here, she was with me the first few days, I was watching it and my grandmother.
vino mi prima acá, estuvo conmigo los primeros días, estaba viéndolo y mi abuela.
是的，直到几天前我和祖母住在一起，那里有我的兄弟、我的表兄弟姐妹、我的朋友。
Yes, until a few days ago I lived with my grandmother, there were my brothers, my cousins, my friends.
Sí, hasta hace unos días atrás vivía con mi abuela, estaban mis hermanos, mis primos, mis amigas.
我的朋友们现在基本上已经在我家安顿下来了，所以我也和我哥哥在一起了。
My friends have now basically settled in my house so I'm with my brother too.
Mis amigos ahora se instalaron en mi casa básicamente así que estoy con mi hermano también.
我很好，因为我好像又重新发现了自己。
I'm fine because it's like I've also rediscovered myself again.
Yo estoy bien porque es como que volví a reencontrarme también conmigo misma.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
这也是我最喜欢的一点。
Which is what I also liked the most about all of this.
que es lo que a mí más me gustó también de todo esto.
你发现你总是得到一些积极的东西。
You saw that you always get something positive.
Viste que siempre sacás algo positivo.
你想重返比赛吗？
Do you want to get back into the race?
¿Tienes ganas de volver a la carrera?
是的，在某个时候我会回来。
Yes, at some point I would return.
Sí, en algún momento volvería.
我认为他们现在很年轻，他们需要你。
I think they are very young now and they need you.
Yo creo que ahora son muy chicos y te necesitan.
我喜欢在那里。
I like to be there.
A mí me gusta estar.
我是努力不花太多时间独处的母亲之一。
I am one of the mothers who tries not to spend so much time alone.
Yo soy de las madres que trato de no irme tanto tiempo sola.
如果你能和他们一起去，我就去。
If you can go with them I'll go.
Si puede ir con ellos voy.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你喜欢足球世界吗？
Do you like the world of football?
¿El mundo del fútbol te gusta?
您是足球迷吗？
Are you a soccer fan?
¿Sos futbolera?
你坏了吗？
Are you broken?
¿Mirás partidos?
你关注他的比赛。
You follow his games.
Le seguís los partidos a él.
不，现在我不太关注它了。
No, now I don't follow it as much.
No, ahora no lo sigo tanto.
我承认，不，不是现在。
I admit, no, not now.
Admito, no, ahora ya.
不，除了时间表有点奇怪之外，几乎都是早上，现在我不太遵守了。
No, besides the schedules are kind of strange, they are almost in the morning, now I don't follow it as much.
No, aparte los horarios son medio raros, son a la mañana casi, ahora no lo sigo tanto.
他正在经历一个伟大的职业时刻，一切都真的完成了。
He is having a great professional moment, everything was really done.
Está pasando un gran momento profesional, se hizo realmente todo.
一切都处于平衡状态，积极。
Everything was on the balance, for positive.
Todo se dio para el balanza, para positivo.
足球迷非常高兴。
The soccer fan is very happy.
El futbolero está como muy contento.
发生在他身上的事情。
of what is happening to him.
de lo que a él le está pasando.
是的，他做得很好。
Yes, he is doing very well.
Sí, le está yendo muy bien.
是的，是的，我总是...
Yes, yes, I always...
Sí, sí, siempre le...
如果他表现出色或者其他什么，他就会告诉奥利，他会把进球奉献给他，我们总是谈论这一点。
If he does well or something, he tells Oli that he is going to dedicate goals to him and we always talk about that.
Si le va bien o algo le dice a Oli que le va a dedicar goles y siempre hablamos de eso.
各方的意见和那。
of the parties and that.
de los partidos y eso.
奥利如何与父亲保持距离？
How does Oli live the distance from his father?
¿Cómo vive Oli la distancia de su papá?
这对她来说很难。
And it's hard for her.
Y a ella se le hace duro.
是的？
Yeah?
¿Sí?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
他问你很多吗？
Does he ask you a lot?
¿Te pregunta mucho?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
我想是的。
I think so.
Creo que sí.
不，这是我最喜欢的话题之一。
No, it is one of the topics that I love the most.
No, es uno de los temas que a mí me encanta más.
分离，不是因为我像个女人，瓦伦蒂娜今天很好。
of the separation, not because I am like a woman and Valentina is fine today.
de la separación, no porque yo soy como mujer y Valentina hoy está bien.
但显然我的孩子们也是伤害我的东西。
But obviously my children are also something that hurts me.
Pero obvio que mis hijos también es algo de que a mí duele.
碰巧我的父母也在我很小的时候就分开了，就像我一样
It happened to me that my parents also separated when I was little and it's like I
a mí me pasó de que mis papás se separaron también cuando yo era chica y es como que me
所有这些都回来了，我看到了奥利，我直接看到了我小时候的自己。
All that comes back and I see Oli and I see myself directly when I was a girl.
vuelve todo eso y yo la veo a Oli y me veo directamente a mí cuando era chica.
而且，显然，作为一个女儿，你永远不希望父母分开，你总是希望他们在一起。
And, obviously, as a daughter you never want your parents to be separated, you always want them to be together.
Y, obvio, uno como hija nunca quiere que sus papás se estén separados, siempre quiere que estén juntos.
除了他们相处得不好之外，他们还会打架，因为有些夫妻会说，好吧，我们分开相处得更好，但是……
except that they get along badly, they fight because there are couples that say, well, we get along better apart, but...
excepto que se lleven mal, se peleen porque hay pareja que dice, bueno nos llevamos mejor separados, pero...
是的，显然我会尽力确保他们一切都好，他们尽可能好，他们花尽可能多的时间与......
Yes, and obviously I am going to try to ensure that they are well, that they are as good as possible, that they spend as much time as they can with...
Sí, y obvio que yo voy a tratar de que ellos estén bien, de que estén lo mejor posible, de que compartan el mayor tiempo que pueden con...
和爸爸一起，这就是我们前进的方式。
with the dad and that's how we're going to get ahead.
con el papá y así vamos a salir adelante.
因为你还必须学习，幸运的是，这种距离是在沟通中。
Because in that you also have to learn, that distance, luckily, is in communication.
Porque en eso también tenés que aprender, que la distancia, por suerte, está en la comunicación.
显然是的。
Obviously yes.
Obvio que sí.
我们进行视频通话之类的，但这是不一样的。
We do video calls and that, but it's not the same.
Hacemos videos llamadas y eso, pero no es lo mismo.
除了你拥有的以外，你不能把它留在屏幕上，你也不能拥有感情、拥抱。
More than what you have, you don't leave it on a screen and you can't have the affection, a hug.
más de que tengas no dejas en una pantalla y el cariño un abrazo no lo puedes tener
这是最让你受伤的部分。
This is the part that hurts you the most.
Es la parte que más te duele todo esto.
最让我受伤的是我的孩子们。
The part that hurts me the most is my children.
A mí la parte que más me duele son mis hijos.
是的，我也对他这么说，因为他们还很年轻。
Yes, and I say it to him too, because they are very young.
Sí, y yo se lo digo a él también, porque son muy chicos.
我知道所有的家庭都会不断地分离，但是这个案子......
And I know that all families continually separate, but the case...
Y yo sé que todas las familias se separan continuamente, pero el caso...
至少在我们的例子中，不同的是，他不想，好吧，他们在周末左右接他们。
At least in our case, the different thing is that he didn't want, well, they picked them up on weekends, or so.
por lo menos en nuestro caso, lo diferente es que no él quería, bueno, los pasaron a buscar los fines de semana, o así.
接触变得有点复杂。
Contact becomes a little more complicated.
el contacto se hace un poco más complicado.
假期快到了吗？
Are the holidays coming?
¿Se vienen las fiestas?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
这将是再次见面的好时机。
and it will be a good time to meet again.
y va a ser un buen momento para reencontrarse.
哦，是的，这就是为什么我也这么决定。
Oh, yes, that's why I decided that way too.
Oh, yo que sí, por eso también lo decidí así.
这一个月迫使我无论如何都要在这里度过。
the month that forced me no matter what to spend here.
el mes que me obligó sí o sí de que pasara acá.
但我也做出了一方面决定。
but I decided on the one hand, too.
pero yo lo decidí por un lado, también.
总而言之，他问我过圣诞节，我告诉他圣诞节，但我决定在这里度过。
It's like all in all, he asked me for Christmas, I told him Christmas, but I decided to spend it here.
Es como que en conjunto, él me pidió de Navidad, yo le dije que Navidad, pero decidí pasarla acá.
由于他们有更多的表兄弟姐妹和一切，打开礼物等时发生的那一刻变得更加美丽
due to the fact that they have more cousins ​​and everything and the moment that happens when opening gifts and so on becomes more beautiful
por el hecho de que ellos tienen más primos y todo y se hace más lindo el momento que pasa a la hora de abrir regalos y demás
如果我们去那里的话，就在 31 号。
And on the 31st if we travel there.
Y el 31 si viajamos para allá.
你是带孩子去旅行吗？
Are you traveling to take the kids?
¿Vos viajás a llevarlo a los chicos?
你打算和家人一起度过你的31岁吗？
And you're going to spend your 31st with your family?
¿Y tú 31 lo vas a pasar con familia?
是的，是的，和恩佐一起，和一切。
Yes, yes, with Enzo, with everything.
Sí, sí, lo con Enzo, con todo.
是的，我们一起度过了，我告诉他，我不会……
Yes, we spent it together, I told him, I'm not going to...
Sí, lo pasamos juntos, le dije, no voy a ir a...
不要独自带着苹果酒去大本钟。
Do not go with a cider to Big Ben alone.
No ir con una cidra al Big Ben sola.
不。
No.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
不，我们一起度过了，是的。
No, we spent it together, yes.
No, lo pasamos juntos, sí.
但你谈过吗？
But did you talk about it?
¿Pero lo charlaste?
不，我们谈得很好。
No, we talked about it well.
No, lo charlamos bien.
是的，他没有问题，我也没有问题。
Yes, he has no problem, neither do I.
Sí, él no tiene ningún problema, yo tampoco.
这就是事情分开的地方，今天我们去玩得很开心，我们将尽一切可能让他们开心。
That's where things separate and today we go and have a good time and we're going to do everything possible to make them happy.
En eso se separan las cosas y hoy vamos y la pasamos bien y vamos a hacer lo posible para que ellos estén felices.
我想对于奥利来说，四岁时，当他明白很多事情时，他会说，好吧，我很快就会见到爸爸，是的。
I imagine that for Oli, at four years old, when he understands a lot of things, well, he says, well, I'll see dad soon, yes.
Me imagino que para Oli, con cuatro años, cuando entiende un montón de cosas, bueno, decir, bueno, pronto veo papá, sí.
不，她今天已经要收拾行李了。
No, she already wants to pack her suitcase today.
No, ella ya quiere armar la valija hoy.
是的，他打电话给他说，还剩几天？
Yes, he calls him on his phone and says, how many days are left?
Sí, lo llama en su y le dice, ¿cuántos días faltan?
还剩多少天？
How many days left?
¿Cuántos días faltan?
是的，不，她很高兴。
Yes, no, she is very happy.
Sí, no, ella está re contenta.
您是和孩子们一起住几天还是孩子们会留在那里？
Are you staying with the kids for a few days or are the kids going to stay there?
¿Te quedás unos días con los chicos o los chicos se van a quedar ahí?
我要住几天。
I'm staying a few days.
Yo me quedo unos días.
我必须在那里完成一些我离开的事情，然后我回到这里，他们和他在一起。
I have to finish doing some things there that I have left and then I come back here and they stay with him.
que tengo que terminar de hacer unas cosas allá que me quedaron y después me vuelvo para acá y ellos se quedan con él.
它会怎样存在呢？
And how is it going to be there?
¿Y ahí cómo va a ser?
这是你们第一次分开吗？
Is this the first time you're going to be separated?
¿Es la primera vez que vas a estar separada?
这是我第一次离开他们，是的。
It's the first time I've left them, yes.
Es la primera vez que los dejo, sí.
来自你的男孩们。
From your boys.
De tus chicos.
每个人都告诉我我不会坚持下去。
Everyone tells me I'm not going to last.
Todos me dicen que no voy a aguantar.
没人放我。
Nobody puts me.
Nadie me pone.
可能是。
Could be.
Puede ser.
我说我要忍受我不知道会发生什么，但每个人都告诉我我会看看。
I said I'm going to endure I don't know what and everyone told me I'm going to see.
Yo dije yo voy a aguantar no sé qué y todos me dicen voy a ver
你给自己限制了多少？
How much did you limit yourself?
¿Cuánto te pusiste de límite?
10天？
10 days?
¿10 días?
不，20。
No, 20.
你是一位非常母亲...
You were a very mother...
Estuviste una madre muy...
20天后我会观察他们的反应，如果我知道婴儿哭得最厉害的话。
20 days I will see how they react, also if I know that the baby is crying more than anything.
20 días voy a ver cómo van reaccionando también si yo sé que está llorando más que nada el bebé
如果我知道他在说妈妈、妈妈、妈妈并且他很想念我，我就会去。
If I know he's saying mom, mom, mom and he misses me a lot, I'll go.
Si yo sé que está diciendo mamá, mamá, mamá y me extraña mucho, voy a ir.
我也不会这么残忍。
I'm not going to be so cruel either.
Tampoco voy a ser tan cruel.
显然，对于帮助别人的恩佐来说。
And to Enzo who helps someone, obviously.
Y a Enzo que la ayuda a alguien, obviamente.
是的，他们有一个从小就认识他们的保姆。
Yes, there is their babysitter who has known them since they were little.
Sí, está la niñera de ellos que los conoce desde que son chiquitos.
所以这也是我保持冷静的原因，因为他必须训练，再次训练，如果有人的话。
So that's also why I stay calm, because he has to train, train again, if there ever is someone.
Así que por eso también me quedo tranquila, porque él tiene que entrenar, volver a entrenar, si así llega a haber alguien.
如果没有，那就非常困难了。
If not, it is very difficult.
Si no, es muy difícil.
一部关于与...有关的妇女和亲属的纪录片即将上映。
A documentary is coming about the women and relatives who had to do with...
Se viene un documental de las mujeres y los familiares que tuvieron que ver con...
通过世界杯，你记录了你的见证。
With the World Cup, you recorded your testimony.
con la Copa del Mundo, vos grabaste tu testimonio.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
你做到了吗？
Did you do it?
¿Lo hiciste?
会发生什么？
What will happen?
¿Qué pasará?
你会吗？
Will you be?
¿Estará?
会吗？
Will it be?
¿Va a estar?
不，我没有问题。
No, I don't have a problem.
No, yo no tengo problema.
我们和恩佐讨论过这个问题，我没有问题。
We talked about it with Enzo and I have no problem.
Lo hablamos con Enzo y yo no tengo problema.
告诉我吧。
Tell me that.
Contame eso.
它怎么样？
How was it?
¿Cómo fue?
你以前做过吗...
Did you do it ago...
¿Vos lo hiciste hace...
多长时间？
how long?
cuánto tiempo?
我是在五月份做的，我在五月份开始录制，并且是美洲杯的一部分。
I did it in May, I started recording, in May and part of the Copa América.
Yo lo hice en mayo, empecé a grabar, en mayo y parte de la Copa América.
这是一部球员全家人都出现的纪录片，对吧？
It's a documentary where the entire family of the players appears, right?
que es un documental donde aparecen toda la familia de los jugadores, ¿no?
是的，不是全部，而是一些。
Yes, not all, but some.
Sí, no todas, sino algunas.
比年轻人更重要。
more than anything like the younger ones.
más que nada como las más jóvenes.
我从五月份开始录音，我在伦敦录制了一部分，在美洲杯上录制了一部分，在阿根廷录制了一部分。
I started recording in May, I recorded part of it in London, I recorded part of it at the Copa América, part of it here in Argentina.
Empecé a grabar en mayo, grabé parte en Londres, grabé parte en la Copa América, parte acá en Argentina.
讲述你的经历。
telling your experience.
contando tu experiencia.
是的，最重要的是，体验是日复一日的。
Yes, more than anything the experience is day to day.
Sí, más que nada la experiencia es el día a día.
恩佐的父母也出现在我们的日常生活中，这是体验世界杯的一部分。
Enzo's parents also appear in our daily lives, part of what it was like to experience the Cup.
El día a día nuestro aparecen también los papás de Enzo, parte de lo que fue vivir la Copa.
您与恩佐讨论的问题是什么？
And what was the question that you discussed with Enzo?
¿Y cuál fue la duda que hablaron con Enzo?
不，我们什么都不谈。
No, we don't talk about any.
No, no hablamos ninguna.
我又说了一句，他要我……这对我来说并不重要，他也告诉了我。
I said one more and he wanted me to... It doesn't matter to me and he told me too.
Dije una más y él quería que... A mí me da lo mismo y él también me dijo.
哦，完美。
Oh, perfect.
Ah, perfecto.
当然，他们问你，他们问制作公司的恩佐你是否可以来这里。
Of course, they asked you, they asked Enzo from the production company if it was okay for you to be here.
Claro, te preguntaron, preguntaron desde el lado de la productora a Enzo si estaba bien que estés.
当然，人们不知道是否……当然。
Of course, one doesn't know if... Of course.
Claro, uno no sabe si... Claro.
不，不，但他们都没有问题。
No, no, but neither of them have problems.
No, no, pero ninguno de los dos tiene problemas.
所以我们会在那里见到你，因为显然他们将成为一家人。
So we're going to see you there because they're going to be family, obviously.
Así que te vamos a ver ahí porque van a ser familia, obviamente.
就是这样，这是已经发生的事情，好吧，现在我看到了其他的事情，但是......
That's it, it's something that already happened and well, now I'm seeing something else, but...
Ya está, es algo que ya pasó y bueno, ahora estoy viendo otra cosa, pero...
好吧，当有人听你说一切都那么好并且假期即将到来时，你会看到第三方......
Okay, when one listens to you and everything is so good and the holidays are going to happen, you saw that the third parties...
Vale, cuando uno te escucha y está todo tan bien y van a pasar las fiestas, viste que los terceros en discordia...
在这种情况下，他们出现了，尼基·尼科尔这个名字......
In this case they appeared, Niki Nicole was the name that...
en este caso aparecieron, Niki Nicole fue el nombre que...
如果他说话，你问恩佐，你告诉他他拒绝了你。
If he spoke, you asked Enzo, you told him that he denied it to you.
que si habló le preguntaste a Enzo, vos lo contaste que él te lo negó.
不，我问过他一个问题，显然我不会参与其中，我会尊重他拥有的女人。
No, I asked him about one, obviously I don't get involved in that and I would respect the woman he has.
No, yo le pregunté por una, obvio que yo en eso no me meto y respetaría a la mujer que tenga él.
从现在开始，因为她就是他的生命。
from now on, because she is his life.
de acá ahora en adelante, porque ella es su vida.
所以没什么，我确实问了他一些事实......
So nothing, I did ask him about a type of fact...
Así que nada, sí le pregunté por un hecho tipo...
要知道为什么我觉得作为一个孩子的妈妈对于天孩子的躁狂是比较多的，他告诉我没有
to know why I think that as a mother of children for the day the children's mania is more, he told me no
para saber porque creo que como madre de los hijos para el día manía de los hijos es más él me dijo que no
所以我确实认识她。
So I did know her.
Así que sí la conocía.
是的，我认识她。
Yes I knew her.
Sí la conocía.
Oliyamanikinikola 正在听歌曲。
Oliyamanikinikola listens to the songs.
Oliyamanikinikola escucha las canciones.
所以我对这个女孩没有任何问题。
So I had no problem with this girl.
Así que yo esta chucha no tenía problema.
当然，你会的。
Of course, you do.
Claro, vos sí.
不，这对我来说并不重要。
No, it doesn't matter to me.
No, a mí me da lo mismo.
你告诉恩佐奥利会听吗？
Did you tell Enzo that Oli listens?
¿Le dijiste a Enzo que Oli escucha?
不，你知道。
No, you know.
No, ya sabe.
哦，你知道，完美。
Oh, you know, perfect.
Ah, ya sabe, perfecto.
好吧，今天她不穷，他们出去杀她什么的也不好。
Well, today she is not poor and it was not good that they went out to kill her or anything.
Bueno, hoy no es pobre y tampoco estaba buena que la salgan a matar a ella ni nada.
但他们确实认识，因为他们有共同点，这就是谣言的来源。
But they do know each other because they shared each other, that's where the rumors come from.
Pero sí se conocen porque compartieron, de ahí salen los rumores.
我不认识她，但是...
I don't know her, but...
Yo no la conozco a ella, pero...
我想他们确实见过一次，不是单独见面，而是一群人见面。
I think they did see each other once, not alone, but in a group.
Creo que sí se vieron alguna vez, no solos, pero en grupo.
他是否告诉你他独自一人，还是你根本不问？
Does he tell you that he is alone or do you not even ask?
¿Él te dice que está solo o vos ni preguntás?
不，我什至不问他，我也不问自己。
No, I don't even ask him, I don't ask myself either.
No, ni le pregunto, yo tampoco me pregunto.
完美的。
Perfect.
Perfecto.
不，我们不讨论这个。
No, we don't get into that.
No, en eso no nos metemos.
是的，我们正在谈论明天确保我们俩的安全。
Yes, we are talking about making sure of both of us tomorrow.
Sí, hablamos que el día de mañana se agurre de los dos.
一段新的关系开始了，我们这样做是出于对彼此的尊重，也是因为我们分享。
A new relationship begins, we do it out of respect for each other and because we share.
empieza una nueva relación, lo hacemos por una cuestión de respeto hacia el otro y porque compartimos.
有两个共同的孩子。
two children in common.
dos hijos en común.
你们住在瓜达拉拉的同一栋楼里。
You are living in the same building in Guadalara.
Estás viviendo en el mismo edificio de Guadalara.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
当阿根廷来的时候，你什么都满足，库纳布埃罗也住在那里。
You are full with everything, Cunabuero also lives there, when Argentina comes.
Estás a full con todo, el Cunabuero también vive ahí, cuando viene la Argentina.
你认识她或她吗？
Do you know her or her?
¿La conocés o guanda?
不，我不认识她。
No, I don't know her.
No, no la conozco.
我可以成为这个团体的一员，从你那里得到一些东西。
I could be part of the group and go get a little out of you.
podría formar parte del grupete e ir a que te saque un poco.
不，但可以肯定。
No, but sure.
No, pero seguro.
如果您要赶周四结束的时间，请小心。
Take care if you are going to catch the end of Thursdays.
Cuídate si vas a agarrar el fin de los jueves.
我可能会在某个时候遇到它。
I'm probably going to come across it at some point.
Seguramente me la voy a cruzar en algún momento.
你觉得这一切怎么样，万达？
What do you think of everything, Wanda?
¿Qué te parece todo Wanda?
你喜欢怎样...
you like how...
te gusta como...
作为一名司机，她所做的事情。
as a driver, what she does.
como conductora, lo que hace.
不，我喜欢，我认为你是一个很有个性的女人。
No, I like it, I think you have a woman with a great personality.
No, a mí me gusta, creo que tenés una mujer con una gran personalidad.
足球朋友们，你们有足球运动员的妻子吗？
Soccer friends, do you have wives of soccer players?
Amigas del fútbol, tenés de mujeres de futbolistas?
是的，他们离开了我。
Yes, they have left me.
Sí, me han quedado.
是的，我也遇到过这样的女人，她们都比较低调，但是……
Yes, I have had women like that, they are all more low profile, but...
Sí, me han quedado mujeres así, son todas más perfil bajo, pero...
我还有女性朋友。
I have women friends left.
Me han quedado mujeres amigas.
您是否参与过女性玩家聊天？
Were you in the female gamer chat or not?
¿Estabas en el chat de mujeres jugadores o no?
是的，有聊天，但只有在...的时候才会说出来。
Yes, there is a chat, but it is only spoken when it is...
Sí, hay un chat, pero que se habla solamente cuando es...
就像一个杯子，一个世界杯。
like a cup, a world cup.
tipo una copa, un mundial.
啊，全是女人。
Ah, there are all the women.
Ah, que ahí están todas las mujeres.
对于组织问题。
for organizational issues.
para temas de organización.
但仅限于这个话题。
But only that topic.
Pero solo ese tema.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
哦，我喜欢它，我喜欢这样。
Oh, I love it, I like that.
Ah, me encanta, me gusta eso.
是的，不，他们很平静。
Yes, no, they are quite calm.
Sí, no, son bastante tranquilas.
嗯，而且你也很冷静。
Well, and you are also very calm.
Bueno, y vos también igual sos muy tranquila.
是的，我很平静。
Yes, I am quite calm.
Sí, yo soy bastante tranquila.
好的，很高兴认识你。
Ok, nice to meet you.
Valen, hermoso conocerte.
谢谢。
Gracias.
谢谢您的光临。
Thank you for coming.
Gracias por haber venido.
我让你有点情绪化了。
I made you a little emotional.
Te hice emocionar un poco.
第一次，今天可能是平常的一天……或者不是？
The first time, today could be an average day... or not?
La primera vez, hoy capaz ser un día medio... ¿o no?
今天只是一天...
And today was just a day that...
Y hoy era justo un día que...
当然，是的。
Sure, yes.
Claro, sí.
但我们没有考虑过。
But we didn't think about it.
Pero no lo pensamos.
但。
But.
Sí, no.
结果是这样的。
It came out like this.
Salió así.
它自发地出来了。
It came out spontaneously.
Salió espontáneo.
结果是这样的。
It came out like this.
Salió así.
所以谢谢你。
So thank you.
Así que gracias.
一个地方。
A place.
Un placer.